派拉蒙电影公司出品
2012年 美国有二百九十四个外交基地遍布全球
美国国务院将它们列入"高危"级别
其中十二处所在地尤为危险
其中两处位于利比亚
的黎波里 和 班加西
2011年10月 美国 法国和英国军队对利比亚发动空袭
在持续空袭的状况下 利比亚人民武装推翻了
穆阿迈尔·卡扎菲长达四十二年的专制统治
这标志着利比亚人民结束了一段
This marks the end of a long and painful chapter
漫长而又痛苦的历史
for the people of Libya,
现在他们有机会在一个
who now have the opportunity
崭新和民主的利比亚当家做主了
to determine their own destiny in a new and democratic Libya.
反对派民兵组织抢占了大批卡扎菲的军火
敌对组织持续抢占
Warring gangs continue to raid
卡扎菲遗留下来的军火库
Gaddafi's abandoned armories
并在利比亚最大的两座城市点燃了战火
as a battle rages in Libya's two largest cities.
地盘争夺大战一触即发
班加西成为了世界上 最危险的地区之一
几乎所有大使馆均已关闭
除了一处美国外交基地和一处中情局秘密基地
为防止致命武器流入全球黑市 中情局对其展开了密切的监视
保护中情局基地的任务
交由六名美军前特种部队精英成员负责
其代号为：G.R.S.
G.R.S.(全球反应人员）雇员以作战经验丰富的退役特种部队士兵为主
他们与CIA签订高薪并拥有超长假期的合同 被派往高危地区执行安保任务
这是一个真实的故事
利比亚 班加西 - 贝尼纳 机场
到 达
装满子弹了
It's loaded.
- 这的队伍怎么样 - 不错
- How's the team here? - Good.
三名前海军陆战队队员 一名前陆军游骑兵
Three ex-Marines, one ex-Army Ranger.
又来个老队友真不错
It's nice having another team guy around.
很高兴见到你 老兄
Good to see you, brother.
回来的感觉真好
Good to be back.
天啊 真热
Oh, man, it's hot!
孩子们怎么样了 杰克
How are the kids, Jack?
孩子们很好
They're good.
他们还向你问好呢
They send their love.
你能相信艾米莉都要上幼儿园了吗
Can you believe Emily's about to start kindergarten?
有约会对象了吗
She dating yet?
你说话最好小心点
You better watch your mouth.
谢天谢地 我家是三个儿子
I thank God I got three boys, man.
杰克 以后你可有苦吃了
You're in for a rough ride, Jack.
这就是"报应" 说得好听点叫"因果"
Payback's a bitch and her stripper name is Karma.
这话是你自己想出来的吗
You come up with that on your own?
在墨西哥的一件T恤上看来的
I saw it on a T-shirt in Mexico.
快看这个
Hey, check this out.
都是革命时留下来的 老兄
Remnants of the revolution, man.
贝基还在气我拉你入伙吗
Is Becky still mad at me for dragging you into contracting?
拜托 她那是生我的气 又不是气你
Oh, come on. She's mad at me, she's not mad at you.
你以前是什么样我可是一清二楚
I'm part of the old crowd, the old Jack.
如今的杰克拎着的是尿不湿而不是M4卡宾枪
The new Jack carries a diaper bag instead of an M4.
这话是泰隆·伍兹说的吗
Is this coming from Tyrone Woods,
那个为他老婆工作的牙科护士
dental nurse, who works for his wife?
你猜怎么着 老兄 我在这可不是了
Guess what? Not out here, brother.
房地产生意怎么样
How's the real estate business?
挺糟糕的
Pretty bad.
有多糟糕
How bad is that?
我都到这来了 不是吗
I'm here, aren't I?
这地方烂透了 杰克
Well, this place sucks, Jack.
不仅仅因为这里热的要死
Not only is it hot as balls,
更因为你无法分辨人们的好坏
but you can't tell the good guys from the bad guys.
- 该死的 - 不不 不是好现象
- Shit. - No, no, no, this isn't good.
该死的
Fuck!
这都是些什么人
Who the fuck are these guys?
我们手上有什么资源
What do we got?
2011年2月17日班加西爆发反政府示威后 卡扎菲军队围剿班加西 反对派撒拉比领导的一个伊斯兰旅率先打响反政府的第一枪 在保卫班加西的战斗中立下头功 从此撒拉比旅被命名为"二月十七日烈士旅"
与我们配合的部队是"二月十七日旅"
The brigade we coordinate with is the February 17th Martyrs.
这可不是他们
This ain't them.
该死的 我们被困住了
Shit, we're boxed in.
需要呼叫支援吗
Are we bailing?
基地 这里是隆
Base, this is Rone.
这里是隆 请回答 完毕
This is Rone. Come in. Over.
基地收到 请说 隆
This is base. Go, Rone.
我被堵在五环路了
I'm in a jam off Fifth Ring Road.
大约有八名武装敌兵在这里
I'm looking at about eight armed Tangos here.
收到 请原地待命
Copy that. Sit tight.
"原地待命" 说的倒是轻松
"Sit tight." That's great advice.
他们有KPV重机枪
They got a KPV.
基地 我们可没空在这耗一整天
Base, we ain't got all day.
隆 他们正在联系二月十七日旅去支援你们
Hey, Rone. They're trying to get Feb 17 to back you up,
但我们也会赶过去
but we're coming.
奥兹 我被堵在五环路上了
Hey, Oz, I'm in a jam off Fifth Ring.
泰
Ty.
隆 已通知二月十七日旅的快速反应部队
Rone, 17 Feb QRF is being alerted.
真是该死
Fuck that.
我只想要我的人组成的快速反应部队
The only Quick Reaction Force I want is my guys.
不行 联系二月十七日旅的快速反应部队
No. Contact 17 Feb QRF.
派他们来 我要我的人
Send them! I want my guys.
跟他们说 统统不准离开基地
Tell them they're not allowed to leave the base.
不行 隆 原地待命
Negative, Rone. Just hang in there.
是我说的不够清楚吗
Maybe I'm not making myself clear.
我面前有一大群拿着AK步枪的激进叛乱分子
I'm looking at multiple radical insurgents with AK's
还有装有50口径机枪的武装皮卡
and a.50-cal technical
那些都够把我的路虎轰到津巴布韦去了 完毕
set to blow my Rover all the way back to Zimbabwe. Over.
我做不了主 兄弟
It's not my call, brother.
来了
Here we go.
欢迎来到班加西
Welcome to Benghazi.
你好
Salaam.
利比亚签证
Libyan visa.
官方认证的 利比亚政府发的
Official. Libyan government.
国际友人 友好点好吗
Friendly? Hmm? Friendly?
停车 接受检查
Pull over for inspection.
不
No.
车停旁边 接受检查
Pull over for inspection!
抱歉 先生 做不到
I'm sorry, sir, I can't do that.
向上看
Look up.
看吧 看上面 看到无人机了吗
Go ahead, look up. You see the drone?
看不见吗 没事 反正无人机能看到你
No? That's all right, because the drone sees you.
清楚地看见你那张脸
Sees your face.
我们知道你是什么人
We know who you are.
如果我们有什么意外 你的家
If anything happens to us, your home,
你的家人 砰 全没了
your family, boom, gone.
下令放我们走
Give the order to let us go.
我要这车
I want the car!
你想都别想
No, I'm not gonna do that.
听着
Look,
我有权来决定自己国家的未来
I earn right to decide the future of my country.
你找错人了
You're talking to the wrong guy.
你愿意为国捐躯吗
How willing are you to die for your country?
我可是随时随地都准备好了
I'm ready to go, right here, right now.
趁我没反悔之前赶快离开
Leave here while you still can.
我们有空中支援吗
We got air support?
我们什么破支援都没有
We don't have any fucking support.
班加西中情局 - 秘密基地 -
警告 受限区域
非授权人士不得入内
看看这些新坐驾
Check the new rides.
卡扎菲倒台后 防弹装甲车大甩卖
Gaddafi had a going-out-of-business sale on armored vehicles.
最高防弹级别 老兄
Max-level armored, man.
我们弄了好几辆
We got a great deal.
都是偷来的
We stole them.
谁让机场没人看管呢
Sat unattended at the airport.
主管
Hey, Chief!
我不想听 泰隆
I don't want to hear it, Tyrone.
没事 没事 我明白
Oh, no, no, I understand.
我知道你在这主张低调
I see what you're going for here.
加固过围墙的秘密间谍基地 门上有监控
Secret spy base with fortified walls, gate cameras,
蓝眼睛的西方人成天在这里进进出出
and blue-eyed Westerners walking in and out of this place all day long.
但要是你想避免...
But if you want to avoid...
真没礼貌
That's so rude.
不敢相信他居然这样对我
Can't believe he just did that to me.
主管 如果你想要避免国际纷争的话
Chief, if you want to avoid an international incident,
就该在我需要自己人时派他们过来
you give me my guys when I ask for them!
当地冲突必须得由当地势力来解决 泰隆
Local faces need to resolve local conflicts, Tyrone.
在这个国家 我们是客人
We're guests in this country.
是不速之客 鲍勃
We're unwanted guests, Bob.
我们是间谍 你们是安保人员
We're spies, you're security guards.
你们的工作就是让我们远离麻烦
Your job is to keep us out of trouble,
而不是把你们自己搅合进去
not get into it yourselves.
那就帮我完成好我的工作 把我的人给我
Well, then help me do my job and give me my guys.
你的人最擅长的事情
Here's what you guys are good at.
就是健健身 还有一天五顿饭
Working out, eating five hot meals a day.
最不擅长的就是听令行事
What you're not so good at is doing what you're told.
五分钟之内把"黄饼"追踪报告给我
I need your trace report on yellowcake in five minutes.
核反应燃料重轴酸胺或重轴酸钠的俗称
马上就好
It's coming.
又称伊斯兰教法虔信者 伊斯兰极端原教旨主义组织 被联合国 英美等国认定为恐怖组织 美国认为其参与了大使馆袭击事件
路障是安萨尔阵线设下的
That roadblock was run by Ansar Al-Sharia.
这已经不仅仅是族群部落和自由斗士的问题了
It's not just tribal groups and freedom fighters anymore.
泰隆 如果你有可靠的情报 请写进备忘录
If you have useful Intel, Tyrone, put it in a memo.
你们住在这里
You guys bunk here,
但你们不是中情局的
but you're not CIA.
你们只是被雇来帮忙的
You're hired help.
本分点
Act the part.
我可是个有修养的人
Where are my manners?
杰克·席尔瓦 这位是倍受尊敬的基地主管
Jack Silva, this is our esteemed Chief of Station.
泰格 你家双胞胎还好吗
Hey, Tig. How are the twins?
- 超可爱 - 真可爱
- Crazy cute. - Cute.
今晚有行动
You have a move tonight.
不侦查一下吗 主管
No recon, Chief?
如果连我的要求都达不到
What makes you Special Operators so special
那你们这些特别行动队又有何特别之处
if you can't do what I need when I need it?
这家伙真有趣
He's fun.
真是有意思
Well, that was fun.
他喜欢摆出那副样子 就因为他有这权力
He gets his jollies pushing around alphas because he can.
在游骑兵学校时 我们也遇到过这样的指挥官
We had this commander back in Ranger school,
他是个货真价实的蠢货
he was a real cockbag.
所以最后一晚
So on our last night,
我和一个兄弟偷了他的贝雷帽
me and a buddy, we stole his beret.
全兵营里的人都"强暴"了它
The whole barracks chubbed it.
- "强暴" - 对 拿小弟弟蹭了它
- "Chubbed it"? - Yeah, rubbed our dicks on it.
美国军方于2002年在古巴关塔那摩湾海军基地所设置的军事监狱 最初的目的是临时关押拘留者
带头的之前是关塔那摩监狱的拘留犯
Leader was a former Gitmo detainee.
那些家伙通常是不记仇的
Yeah, those guys usually don't hold a grudge.
杰克 我是马克·盖斯特
Jack. Mark Geist.
叫我奥兹 很荣幸见到你
Oz. Pleasure.
抱歉老兄 大家注意 这位是杰克·席尔瓦
Oh, brother, I'm sorry. Everybody, this is Jack Silva.
这是我们第三次合作了 他知道该怎么做
It's our third contract together, so he knows the drill.
我们是在科罗纳多海豹突击队训练时认识的
We met training SEALs at Coronado.
你是怎么教"海豹"用鼻子顶球的
How do you get them to balance that beach ball on their nose?
太难了
It's tough.
我们这有三名前海军陆战队员 还有一位喜欢
So we got three ex-Marines here and one ex-Army retard
把自己下体到处塞的前陆军游骑兵
who likes to rub his dick on things.
我是克里斯·帕朗托 叫我坦托就行
Kris Paronto. Call me Tanto.
你好 我是泰格
Hey, man. I'm Tig.
泰格在这里待的最久
Tig's been here the longest,
他会带你尽快熟悉这一片的
so he'll get you up to speed on the area.
这是布恩 侦查狙击手 禅宗大师
This is Boon. Scout Sniper, Zen Master,
算是坦托的"监护人"
holder of Tanto's leash.
欢迎来到地中海俱乐部
Welcome to Club Med.
这里从六月起就进入旱季了
So it hasn't rained since June,
直到九月才会开始下雨
it's not gonna rain again until September.
你睡双人间 不跟我一起 因为我是管事的
You're double-bunked. Not me, because I'm in charge.
健身房烂到不行 伙食倒是不错
The gym sucks, food's actually good.
基地主管就是个二货
And the Base Chief is kind of a tool.
他今天是挺混蛋
Well, he's a dick today.
也许他只是想要顶新帽子
Maybe he just needs a new hat.
别鼓励他了
Don't encourage him.
别这样 他只是在做本职工作罢了
Oh, come on. He's a guy with a job to do.
他只想熬到退休 但说起他的话
He's playing his string out, but you talk to him,
鲍勃以前还是有些功绩的
Bob did some shit back in the day.
好了 杰克 这是白板
All right, Jack, this is the whiteboard
这块板将决定你接下来六十天的生活作息
that's gonna run your life for the next 60 days.
我希望你每小时都查看一次
I want you to check it every hour,
因为紧急任务随时都会有 比如说
because last-minute moves pop up every minute, such as
三小时后 我们就有一次任务
we're shotgunning it in three hours.
三小时 我接到简报后会通知你们的
Three hours. I'll let you know when I'm briefed.
这里原本是一处私家宅院
This was a private family compound
属于一名利比亚富人
owned by a wealthy Libyan
他在革命发起之后离开了
who got out of town after the revolution
把这里租给了中情局
and leased it to the CIA.
他很聪明
He was smart.
味道有点难闻
A little pungent.
一点间谍情报技术
A little spy tradecraft.
谁能想到美国人会
Who'd expect Americans to be
屈尊躲在臭气熏天的屠宰场旁边呢
hiding out next to a stank-ass slaughterhouse?
我们称之为"僵尸之地"
We call it Zombieland.
A B C D 四栋楼
Building A, B, C, D.
- 哈沙姆 - 在 长官
- Hesham! - Yes, sir.
来了 长官
Yes, sir.
谢谢 谢谢 长官
Thank you. Thank you, sir.
他人不错
He's a good man.
但有些人得防着点
But there's a few we got our eyes on,
所以要时刻保持警惕
so always stay strapped.
该死的孩子
Damn kids!
这里是浴室
This is the bathroom.
你睡这里
This is you.
我睡那里
That's me.
这个帘子就是防止
This curtain is meant to
你对我投怀送抱的 所以...
discourage you from spooning with me. So...
爸爸 你离开这里要去做什么工作
Daddy, what do you do when you go away for work?
就不能在这边工作吗
Can't you work here?
我们可以做树屋生意赚钱
We could have a treehouse business.
听起来很棒
That sounds amazing.
那我们就能永远在一起了
Then we could always be together.
你知道孩子们需要的不是树屋 杰克
You know, the girls don't need a treehouse, Jack.
她们需要的是你
They need you.
我只希望 你不会在某天醒来时才意识到
I just hope that one day, you're not gonna wake up and realize
你已经错失了人生最美好的部分
you missed the best part of life.
你们这些人都结婚生子了
You contractors are all married with kids,
但没有一个人戴婚戒 这是为什么呢
yet none of you wear wedding rings. Why is that?
我们的工作就是识人
Our job is reading people.
所以我们不能给任何人可乘之机
So, we can't give anyone an edge,
特别是可能会利用这一点的坏人
especially bad guys that might use it.
我知道你和泰隆的交情颇深 我就直说了吧
I know you and Tyrone go way back, so I'll be frank.
中情局觉得你们应该在这里 但我不觉得
The company thinks you should be here. I don't.
事实是 这里根本就没什么真正的威胁
Truth is, there is no real threat here.
我们为这些人赢得了革命
We won the revolution for these people.
而这里的枪支越多
The more guns there are here,
人们之间的误会可能就越深
the more likely there is to be a misunderstanding.
这是我退休前的最后一站
This is my last station before retiring.
我不想出现任何误会
I don't need a misunderstanding.
听明白了吗
Is that clear?
明白了
Loud and.
这是你们的通行证 还有两周花销
These are your credentials, two weeks per Diem.
要是我 我就赶紧花 班加西的局势瞬息万变
I'd spend them quick. Things change fast here in Benghazi.
美国间谍学校 中情局特工培训基地
我们这有"农场"培养出来的精英
We have the brightest minds from the Farm,
在哈佛和耶鲁受过高等教育
educated at Harvard and Yale,
他们干着至关重要的工作
doing important work.
你最好不要妨碍他们
Best thing for you to do is stay out of their way.
草
Fuck!
安静点
Quiet!
你就跟个野兽似的
You act like animals!
派佩餐馆的近距离保护行动
It's a CPU at Pepe's.
伙计们 这没什么难度
It's all pretty simple stuff, guys.
公共场所会面
Public meet.
利比亚石油公司的高管和他的妻子
Libyan oil company exec and his wife.
情报负责人是韦纳尔和吉莉安妮
Case Officers Vayner and Jillani.
吉莉安妮"发展"这个人好几个月了
Jillani's been developing this guy for months.
"发展"是间谍之间的新暗号
"Developing" Is their new tech word for spy shit.
杰克 鉴于这是你第一次和我们出任务
Jack, since this is your first time with us,
你就负责扮演吉莉安妮的丈夫
you're gonna be posing as Jillani's husband.
我上周才跟她上过床
I rode bitch last week.
她可泼辣了
She's a little spicy.
奥兹 泰格 去豪华轿车
Oz, Tig, limo.
布恩 坦托 紧跟其后
Boon, Tanto, follow.
那你呢
You?
我开车
I drive.
杰克 这是索娜
Hey, Jack, this is Sona,
她是在法国长大的美国人
she's an American who grew up in France,
所以她十分的友好
which makes her really friendly.
你好
Nice to meet you.
小心点 杰克 我觉得她是在跟你调情
Careful, Jack, I think she's flirting with you.
好了 我们不用表现的那么友好了
Okay. Let's keep the make-nice to a minimum.
我打算今晚就引他上钩
I want to hook this guy tonight.
他想跟我们合作
He wants to work with us.
太心急你会把他吓走的
Move too fast and you'll frighten him off.
我知道该怎么做
I know how to do this!
他才是新来的
He's new.
我对这工作不陌生
Not to this.
我不明白
I don't understand.
为什么他们总是给我们换安保人员
Why do they keep changing security guards on us?
他们觉得我们需要保姆
They think we need babysitting.
好 喝你的咖啡 别试图帮忙
Okay. So just drink your coffee. Don't try to help.
也不要说话
Don't talk, either.
世界上最大的非政府石油天然气生产商
我是娜吉娅 来自埃克森美孚公司的说客
My name is "Nazia," A lobbyist for Exxon Mobil.
布里特就是皮特 我的老板 你是我丈夫杰克
Brit is "Peter," My boss. And you're my husband, "Jack."
等等
Hang on.
杰克是我的真名
Jack's my real name.
真的吗
It is?
真是太棒了
Fantastic.
很高兴再次见到你 法瑞德
It's nice to see you again, Fahreed.
请让我介绍一下 这是我老板皮特
Let me introduce you to my boss, Peter.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - Hello.
他是杰克 我的丈夫
And this is Jack, my husband.
- 你好 - 很高兴认识你
- How are you? - Very nice to meet you.
这是我妻子
This is my wife.
很高兴见到你
Nice meeting you.
这是最好的意大利餐厅 快来
Oh. This is the best Italian restaurant. Come.
太棒了
Oh, fantastic.
- 你先请 - 谢谢
- Please, after you. - Thank you.
怎么了
What's up?
奥兹 他们进去了 你看到了吗
Hey, Oz. They're in. You got eyes?
看到了 在这里享受意大利廉价咖啡
Yeah, just enjoying a little Italian beanery here.
你一定不知道好的咖啡豆
You wouldn't know a good coffee
是从松鼠屎里提取出来的 乡巴佬
bean from a lump of squirrel shit, country boy.
就是提醒你出来的时候记得
Just make sure you pick me up a bag of
给我拿一袋阿拉伯香浓咖啡豆
that whole bean Arabic Intense on the way out.
法瑞德 以后你可以用这个手机联系我们
Fahreed, you can contact us with this phone in the future.
好的
Good.
如果你三天内给我打电话
And if you give me a call in three days,
我很乐意看看货运清单
I would love to see the manifest,
然后我们可以谈谈细节
and we can go over the details.
- 非常好 - 很棒
- Very good. - Perfect.
喂
Hey.
主管的首要规矩是什么
What's the Chief's number-one rule?
不要下车吗
Don't get out of the car?
对 我现在要下车了
No, I'm getting out of the car.
他行动了
He's on the move.
开罗太棒了
Cairo is great!
那是一座被低估了的城市
Now, that is an underrated city.
我最喜欢的是尼罗河流域
What I really love is the Nile Valley.
尼罗河流域太美丽了
The Nile Valley is beautiful.
是的 非常美 但那里太拥挤了
Yes, it's beautiful, but it's too busy.
我们今天早上吵了一架
We had a bit of a fight this morning.
不 我们没有
No, we didn't.
很实惠 两把 先生 很实惠
Good price. Two. Two, sir. Good price.
火箭炮
The rocket.
俄国的火箭炮
Russian rocket.
快点 奥兹 快接电话
Come on, Oz, pick up the phone.
我们在认真考虑拓展叙利亚的市场
We are weighing a serious move on the Syrian market.
我们得走了
We got to go.
所以我们非常需要你的船运支持
So, that's why we really need your shipping support.
抱歉赶时间 保姆问题
Sorry to rush off. Babysitter.
抱歉 但我们会保持联系的
I'm so sorry, but we will be in touch.
抱歉
Sorry again.
我们走 快走
Let's go. Go, go, go.
走 走 走
Go, go, go.
走 走 走 上车
Go, go, go. Get in.
你再这样对我试试
Don't you ever handle me like that again!
你他妈以为你是谁
Who the fuck do you think you are?
你不该下车的 不该下车
You never get out of the car, ever!
你刚把会面搞砸了
You just fucking blew that meet.
我们被跟踪了
Picked up a tail.
看到那绿货车吗 那就是跟踪我们的人
See the green van? That's your tail.
甩掉他们
Shake and bake!
你身后绿色的车 我们来搞定
Green van behind you. We're on it.
左转 之后再左转一次
Make a left, then another left.
这是我第二次战地工作了
This is my second war tour!
我知道自己在做什么
I know what I'm fucking doing.
这是我第十二次了
Well, this is my 12th.
如果他们拍了我们的照片 我们需要拿回来
If they got pictures of us, then we need to get them.
我也想 但是那不是我们的职责
I would love to, but that's not our job.
"只能保护 不准交战" 这是主管的命令
"Protect, not engage." The Chief's orders.
他们就在后面
Got 'em right behind.
他妈的从这路上滚开
Get out of the fucking road!
- 小心 - 隆 从你左边过来了
- Oh, careful. - Rone, coming up on your left!
借过
Excuse me.
抱歉 换个位置
Pardon me. Switch sides.
他跟得很紧 他要采取行动了
He's on you tight, man. He's getting aggressive.
是的 我看到他了 我看到了
Yeah. I see him. I see him.
杰克 如果他靠的太近 就干掉他
Jack, if he gets too close, drop him.
小心
Watch out!
我是没上过哈佛大学
I might not have gone to Harvard,
但是我确定那是跟踪者
but I'm pretty sure that was a tail.
五周后
孩子们
Hey, guys.
- 爸爸 - 爸爸
- Hi, Daddy! - Hi, Daddy!
见到你们真开心
Hey! Good to see you.
孩子们 来 见见我的新朋友
Guys, guys, take a look. Meet my new friend.
- 是不是很酷 - 好恶心
- Isn't he cool? - Ew. It's gross!
它可是抓苍蝇的大师
He is a grand master at catching flies.
他成天就在坐在这里等着 一次抓一只
All day, he just sits here and grabs one at a time.
你准备刮胡子吗 爸爸
Are you gonna shave your beard, Daddy?
那要看你们的妈妈怎么想了
Well, depends on what Mommy thinks.
贝基 你觉得怎么样
Beck, what do you think?
帅呆了
Very handsome.
幼儿园怎么样
How's kindergarten, Em?
今天轮到我喂温斯顿了
Today is my turn to feed Winston.
非常酷
Very cool, very cool.
温斯顿是谁
Who is Winston?
他是班里的金鱼
He's the class goldfish!
妈妈说周末我可以把他带回家
Mommy says I can bring him home one weekend.
有个男人在家感觉不错 是不是
Be nice to have a man around the house, huh?
- 好吧 - 现在我们能去玩了吗
- Okay. - Can we go play now?
全球反应人员会议室集合
GRS meet in the team room.
一切都还好吗
Is everything okay?
宝贝 我大概得挂了
Babe, I think I got to go.
那是泰吗
Was that Ty?
只是个集合口令 可能什么事都没有
It's just a muster call. It's probably nothing.
- 好的 - 抱歉
- Okay. - Sorry.
告诉孩子们 我爱她们 好吧
Just tell the girls I say I love them, all right?
我明天再给你打电话
I'll call you tomorrow.
我爱你 拜拜
I love you. Bye.
席尔瓦 和平时一样 你他妈又迟到了
Silva! You're fucking late! As usual.
格伦·道尔蒂 最近怎么样 兄弟
Glen Doherty. What's up, brother?
隆说你在的黎波里 有什么大事
Rone said you were in Tripoli. What's the occasion?
克利斯·史蒂文斯大使周一上午
Ambassador Chris Stevens is coming in
要从的黎波里过来
from Tripoli monday morning.
你那时候都到家了
Well, you'll be home.
不 我们三个人延期了
Not anymore. Three of us extended.
大使坚持要住在领事馆内
The Ambassador is staying at the Special Mission Compound at his own insistence.
我知道 我知道这很麻烦
I know. I know it's a problem.
但问题是
And here's the thing.
大使不是什么肤浅无知的政客
The Ambassador isn't some dilettante political appointee.
他是动真格的
He's the real deal.
虔诚的信徒
A true believer.
他是去那里赢得民心的
He's there to win hearts and minds.
要是住在官方上并不存在的秘密基地
Now, he can't very well do that operating
收买人心的工作可不好做
out of a classified facility that doesn't officially exist.
如果他整天在领事馆处理国家大事的话
If he's racking at the consulate with his State detail,
那能和我们扯上什么关系
then what fuck does this have to do with us?
他没有随行人员 只有两个安保人员
He's traveling with no staff, just a two-man security team.
那些人没有你们了解这座城市
Now, the State guys don't know the city like you guys do.
大使坚持要用当地司机
The Ambassador insisted on local drivers,
但在这一点上 我们争赢了
but we won that argument.
- 所以现在我们是司机了 - 是的
- So we're chauffeurs now. - Yeah.
训练有素的高薪司机
Highly trained, highly paid chauffeurs.
主管不会同意的 他什么都不想让我们做
Chief won't go for it. He doesn't want us doing anything.
他是不同意 但这是上级的意思
He didn't go for it. But he got outranked.
大使应该得到最好的服务
Now, the Ambassador deserves the best,
那就是全球反应人员了 对吧
and that's GRS, right?
那里 那些人
Hey. Right here. These dudes.
这就是上次跟踪你时 撞了拖车的人的房子
Bad guy house your tail van got towed to.
笑一笑 混蛋们
Yeah, smile, motherfuckers.
这里距离领事馆只有两个街区
It's just two blocks from the compound.
2012年9月9日 星期日 美国外交基地
好了 怎么回事
All right. Hey, what's the problem?
首先 让他们冷静下来
First of all, tell them to calm down.
各位 他妈的都小点声
Everybody, dial it the fuck down!
好了 怎么回事
All right, what is the problem?
是二月十七日旅 这些人真有趣
17 Feb. These guys look like fun.
不能罢工 好吗 回去工作
There will be no striking. All right? Get back to work.
如果你每天为了二十八美元
How would you feel if you had to
而不得不保护美国人
protect Americans at $28 a day
还要自备弹药 你会怎么想
and then bring your own bullets?
所以该把安保工作交给专业人士 对吧
Well, why leave security to the professionals, right?
先生们
Gentlemen!
欢迎来到别墅
Welcome to the casa.
这个月来参加丑胡子大赛挑错时间了
You guys picked the wrong month for a bad mustache competition.
几百块钱打水漂了
Hundred bucks on the line.
这个肯定稳操胜券
Got this one in the bag.
我是斯科特·威克兰德
Scott Wickland.
我是泰隆·伍兹
Tyrone Woods.
我是戴夫·乌本
Dave Ubben.
来吧 我带你们去参观一下
Come on. Let me give you the grand tour.
我能明白
I can relate.
这里就像凯撒酒店的大厅一样
It's like the lobby at Caesars.
- 我的天 - 太他妈棒了
- Damn! - Shit's bangin'.
让你忘却自己身处班加西
Makes you forget you're in Benghazi.
伙计们 我是亚力克探员
Hey, guys. I'm Agent Alec.
刚刚在门外和一群不上道的中东警察
Just dealing with some Middle Eastern Keystone Cops
打交道
out at the gate.
那些家伙经常大喊大叫
Those guys yell a lot.
你们这里布局如何
What's your setup here?
大使住的这半边别墅 属于安全区域
Our Ambo's residence in this half of the villa is the safe haven.
入口加固 防爆门
Forced-entry, blast-resistant door.
窗户上有安全围栏
Security bars on the windows.
里面是我们安全屋
Inside that is our safe room.
大使有实战经验吗
Ambo have any tactical experience?
没有 但他有我们
Nah. He has us.
院子占地九英亩 场地是三角形
So, it's a nine-acre compound, shotgun style
从这里
from here,
一直到后面结束
all the way to the back.
我带你去那里
I'll take you there.
在他的房间
His room links to
可以与华盛顿特区和的黎波里直接联系
State in D.C. and Tripoli.
- 这里是管控中心吗 - 是的
- That's the TOC? - Yeah.
那是后门
Back gate?
只有一条路 紧急出口
One way only. Emergency exit.
找了些二月十七日旅的人负责保安和监控
Got a couple 17 Febs on detail, cameras.
那里上锁了
It's locked.
除了冲锋枪 你们还有什么别的武器
What kind of firepower you guys carry other than assault rifles?
我们还有许多小型武器
We've got multiple small arms.
弹药位于酒吧后面的管控中心
And ammo in the TacOps Center just beyond the cantina.
这边走
That way.
就这些吗
That's it?
我以为每个大使馆
I thought every embassy
都有硬性的安保标准
had standard hard-target security measures.
防止汽车炸弹的路障 全天士兵巡岗
Car bomb barricades, full-time Marines.
本应是这样的
Supposed to.
这里不是大使馆
This isn't an embassy.
而是临时的外交基地
We're a temporary diplomatic outpost.
美国现在预算有限
Uncle Sam's on a budget right now,
所以 我想是不可能有往常的安保规格了
so I guess normal security regulations don't apply.
果然是政府的做事风格
Man, that's some real "Dot-gov" Shit, huh?
这里就像是我们的度假胜地
It's like our own little resort.
我不想说扫兴的话 女士们
I hate to piss on your party, ladies,
但五个拿着M4卡宾枪的人是远远不够用的
but five dudes with M4s is not enough.
前门的本地人根本起不到作用
The locals on your front gate are worthless,
周围防卫太弱
perimeter's soft,
整个院子就他妈是个狙击手的天堂
and this whole compound's a fucking sniper's paradise.
如果有人用重型武器攻击这里
Any big element gets inside here,
你们都他妈会没命
you guys are gonna fucking die.
说的真感人
Well, that's heartwarming.
什么
What?
无意冒犯
No offense.
伙计们 我们就在一英里外
Guys, we're a mile down the road.
如有有什么事情 呼叫我们
Anything goes down, you call us,
我派布恩来 你们就没事了
I send Boon, you're good.
保重 伙计们
Take care, guys.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
他们两个的军事经验加起来最多就十几年吧
A dozen years of military experience between them, max?
这周肯定很有意思
Gonna be a fun week.
2012年9月10日 星期一
吉布提 请求重新校准扫描鹰无人机
Djibouti, request retasking ScanEagle.
收到 两个目标都已锁定
Copy that. I have eyes on both.
奥兹 狙击手掩护 就位
Oz, sniper over-watch. Get in position.
阿莫尔 你一直生活在这里 是吧
Amahl, you lived here all your life, right?
是的
Yes.
卡扎菲真的只雇佣女性
Is it true Gaddafi only hired females
保护他的个人安危吗
for his personal security detail?
是的 千真万确
Yes. That is accurate.
卡扎菲是个十恶不赦的混蛋 但并不蠢
Gaddafi might've been an evil asshole, but he wasn't stupid.
我讨厌这个环节
I hate this part.
准备了 伙计们
Here we go, guys.
奥兹 行动
Oz, let's rock.
我瞄准右面的那个皮包骨
I got the skinny on the right.
那我来搞定剩下那个疯子
Let me take the whack-out guy.
阿莫尔 让这家伙冷静下来
Amahl, tell this guy to calm down.
冷静 冷静
Easy, easy.
他让你们把武器放下
He's saying bring your weapon down.
他想要他的钱
He wants his money.
好的 好的
Okay, okay.
这是你的钱
This is your money.
阿莫尔 让这该死的家伙冷静下来
Amahl, tell this guy to calm the fuck down.
那家伙像发了疯一样
That guy's whacked.
你的钱
Your money.
大块头
Hey, big man!
伙计 你好
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey, hey! Jambo.
你知道"你好"的手势 对吧
You know the jambo, yeah?
别冲动
Come on.
好了 冷静 好吗
Okay, cool down. Okay?
冷静 宝贝
Cool, baby.
走吧
Come on.
那家伙差点就发疯了
That guy almost lost his head.
基地 我们没事
Base, we are good.
雇佣军都认得"你好"的手势
Mercenaries all know the jambo, Amahl.
他们不会出问题了
These guys are all right.
基地 我们看到很多俄国产SA-7防空导弹
Base, we're looking at a lot of Russian SA-7s.
让他尽量盯紧卡车
Tell him to maintain eyes on the truck as long as he can.
我们要找到他的藏匿地
We're gonna find his stash
然后用地狱火导弹将那里夷为平地
and we're gonna level it with a Hellfire.
你好 我是克利斯·史蒂文斯
Hi. Hi, Chris Stevens.
- 我是索娜 - 索娜 幸会 鲍勃
- Sona. - Sona, nice to meet you. Bob.
- 谢谢你这样做 - 是我的荣幸
- Thank you for doing that. - It's my pleasure.
- 这意义非凡 - 能回来真好
- It means a lot. - So good to be back.
这是我们的观察员艾伦
This is our CDOB, Alan.
我是布里特·韦纳尔
Brit Vayner.
艾伦 我是克利斯·史蒂文斯 布里特 幸会
Alan, Chris Stevens. Brit, pleasure.
先生们 大家好 我是克利斯·史蒂文斯
Gentlemen, greetings. Chris Stevens.
久仰大名 大使先生
Pleasure to meet you, Mr. Ambassador.
幸会 进去吧
Nice to meet you. Step on in.
在看到了穆尔西在埃及的一系列举动
So between what we see happening in Egypt with Morsi
穆罕穆德·穆尔西上任后造成了一系列的政治变动
以及叙利亚当前的动荡局面后
and the current destabilization of Syria,
没错 我们很容易想象出
yes, it's easy to imagine
在这里可能发生的一切局面
any number of scenarios playing out here.
然而 在我看来
However, in my mind,
若不将目前的情形视为机遇
our biggest mistake would be
将会是我们最大的失误
to not view this moment as an opportunity.
政府间的关系十分重要 这没错
Relationships between governments are important, yes,
但我们与人民间的关系
but relationships between people
才是外交的根本
are the real foundation of diplomacy.
作为美国人 我们的使命就是要
And I believe that it is our mission as Americans
帮助班加西人民建立一个
to help Benghazans form
自由 民主 繁荣的利比亚
a free, democratic and prosperous Libya.
好了 谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
到我办公室来 立刻
In my office, now.
不用道歉 我会去说的
Don't bother apologizing. I'll do it.
我不会道歉
Well, I won't.
因为这种自吹自擂的政治发展演讲
'Cause I've heard the rah-rah speech about politics and progress
我已经听过无数次了
a hundred goddamn times before.
那我就把你上报给上级
Well, then I'll write you up.
真贴心
Sweet.
主管 这家伙只睡了两小时
Chief. Chief, the guy's going on two hours sleep.
他昨晚有侦察任务
He had a late scout last night
今天一大早又出去回购武器
and an early buyback this morning.
没错 要买光卡扎菲的所有武器
Yeah, buying up all of Gaddafi's arms.
就和去沙滩上
Let's count the fucking
数清有多少沙粒一样不靠谱
sand particles on the beach while we're at it.
SA-7防空导弹也被称为SA-7"圣杯"
你从黑市里带回来的三十枚SA-7防空导弹
Those 30 Grails that you took off the black market,
相当于保护了三十架飞机不被击落
that's 30 airplanes that don't go down.
我受够你了 坦托
I'm so sick of your shit, Tanto.
如果你不能表现的专业点
If you can't figure out how to act like a professional,
还有十多个人等着接你的饭碗
there are 10 guys waiting to take your spot.
而且我相信
And I'm sure that
你应该很高兴继续回去当你的保险公估人吧
you'll be happy at home being an insurance adjuster.
这是最后一次机会了 泰隆
That's the last chance, Tyrone.
好了 全球反应人员
All right. GRS,
大使在市长办公室有一个私人会议
the Ambassador has a private meet at the Mayor's office.
所以我们要低调行事
So, we're looking at a low-profile event.
我们是来帮忙的 所以不引人注目就行
We're here to back up State, so just stay in the background.
大使进来了 戴夫 你负责右侧
Ambo's entering. Dave, take right side.
这是怎么回事 这是在逗我吧
Oh. What is this? You've got to be kidding me.
这就是所谓的低调行事吗
So much for a low profile.
妈的 谁让他们进来的
Fuck me. Who let them in?
美国为你们而来
America is here for you.
没错
We are.
这事 就是这些破事让我惹我妻子生气
This? This is the shit that pisses my wife off.
这里的任何一个人都可以射穿他的上衣
Any one of these people could klack off a vest.
至少那样死得快 兄弟
At least it'll be quick, brother.
别这么混蛋
Don't be an asshole.
许多国家纷纷涌现出来
A number of countries have come forth
提供贷款 土耳其最近也参与其中
and offered loans, most recently Turkey.
谢谢 先生们
Thank you, gentlemen.
先生 明天的事情说定了吗
Sir. Are we clear on tomorrow?
鉴于明天是911纪念日
I have been persuaded in an abundance of caution
我已经被警告过无数次
to remain inside the compound walls all day,
要在领事馆里呆一整天了
given the 9/11 anniversary,
所以不需要司机了
so no drivers needed.
晚安
Good night.
这些民兵 他们拥有的数不清的军火
These militias, they have unlimited firepower
而且他们之间可以协作
and they can coordinate.
你得尽可能的让他保持低调
You've got to keep his moves low.
是的 今天本来不该对外开放的
Yeah, it was supposed to be closed door.
但市议会中有人向媒体泄露了消息
Someone from the city council tipped the media.
这是西恩·史密斯
Sean Smith,
这是来自中情局基地的隆 杰克和泰格
meet Rone, Jack and Tig from the annex.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - How you doing?
西恩是来这里为大使安装安全通讯设备的
Sean was sent here to install secure comms for the Ambo.
结果还帮我们升级了无线网络
Ended up supercharging our Wi-Fi.
希望他也能去我们那一趟
Wish he could do that at our residence.
我有安全许可
I got security clearance.
也许这周晚些时候我就能过去
Maybe later this week I'll come by.
先生们 我们在这里不会有事的
Gentlemen, we should be good here.
稍后再和你们联系 好好休息一天吧
Call you later to check in. Have a nice day off.
- 任务如何 - 他就像个明星
- How'd it go? - He's a rock star.
班加西的所有人都知道他在那
Everybody in Benghazi knew he'd be there.
等等 不不 就是这个 就是这个
Oh, wait, no, no. This is it. This is it.
到唐尼的台词了 等等
This is Downey's line. Hold on.
我 我知道我是谁
Me? I know who I am!
美国喜剧动作片"热带惊雷"中的台词 小罗伯特·唐尼主演
我在扮演一个正在扮演别人的人
I'm just a dude playing a dude disguised as another dude.
经典之作
Classic.
来自美国国务院
From the U.S. Department of State.
"注意 据称西方某机构
"Be advised. Reports that a Western facility
或美国的军事基地下周可能会遭到攻击"
Or U.S. Installation may be attacked in the next week."
阅后销毁
Read and destroy.
2012年9月11日 星期二
回到班加西感觉太好了
It is so nice to be back in Benghazi.
情感维系变得更强了...
Much stronger emotional connection...
绿树成荫 宽敞美丽的院子
Green, spacious, beautiful compound.
再次与二月十七日旅合作...
Reconnected with February 17th...
安保是个大问题
Security is a big concern.
今天看见有人在对着领事馆拍照
Saw people taking photos of the compound today.
感觉这里不安全 我的人都很关注这个问题
Feel unsafe here. My guys are concerned.
武器市场上的枪支
...guns at arms bazaars...
已向的黎波里汇报
Voiced it to Tripoli.
事情都乱了套
It's crazy.
尼克
Hey, Nick?
这是我第二次看到他们了
It's the second time I've noticed it.
尼克 戴夫
Hey, Nick, Dave?
去问问二月十七日旅在后门看到什么人了吗
See if Feb 17 saw anybody at the back gate.
派一个懂阿拉伯语的人去
Well, get somebody who speaks Arabic
以便我们问他们问题
so we can ask them a question.
来吧 让她也加入视频
Yeah, come on, put her on the phone.
嘿 宝贝
Oh! Hey, baby.
孩子们发现它喜欢吃多力多滋玉米片
Kid's discovered she likes Doritos.
没错
Yeah!
好了 没事
Yeah, that's okay.
你可以吃它 尝尝它的味道
You can eat it. You can taste it.
没错 小家伙 看看你的眼睛
Yeah, buddy, look at your eyes.
看看 他长得像谁
Look at that. Who does he look like?
什么
What?
我女儿喝酒了
Daughter's drinking.
你十五岁就开始喝酒了
You drank when you were 15.
小女孩可不该喝酒
Little girls don't drink.
迪士尼乐园 你们真幸运
Disneyland? How lucky are you guys?
- 你们等会儿骑什么玩 - 大怪兽
- What are you guys gonna ride? - Jumbo.
小飞象 不是大怪兽 是小飞象
Dumbo, not Jumbo. Dumbo.
艾米莉 你谢谢妈妈了吗 说谢谢了吗
Em, did you thank Mommy? Say thank you?
- 我们说了 - 说了
- Yes, we did. - Yes.
我觉得你们没说
I don't think you did.
什么 好的 我给他们看个东西 别挂
Huh? Yeah, I'll show them. Hold on.
宝贝 我可不会那么快
Baby, that's not me.
怎么能这样说呢 看看这个
That's mean. Look at this.
一点二秒之后 交配就结束了
...mate for 1.2 seconds and the act is complete.
你为什么要发这个
Why would you send that?
如果真是这样
Anyway, if it was,
那就是你生命中最美妙的三秒钟
it'd be the best three seconds of your life.
我们很想你 注意安全 爱你
We miss you. Be safe. We love you.
我也爱你们
Yeah, I love you, too.
他在做什么
What's he doing?
我想啃啃那肉嘟嘟的胳膊 真可爱
I want to eat those fleshy arms! Come on!
人寿保险办好了吗
What about the life insurance?
这是第二次提醒你了
This is the second notice.
你得去把钱付了
You gotta... You got to pay it.
好的 我会去办的
Okay, okay, I'll figure it out.
我们家前院的那棵橡树怎么样了
And what are we doing about the oak tree in the front lawn?
移除它需要七百美金
The removal's $700...
不对 是一千二 不是七百
No, it's $1,200, not $700.
那家伙简直是在敲诈我
The guy's trying to rip me off.
贝基 听着 我两周后就回来了 好吗
Becky, Becky, listen. I'll be home in two weeks. Okay?
我能自己把它移掉
So I'll take it down myself.
那我们就真的要买人寿保险了
Then we're really gonna need life insurance.
我知道 我在...
I know, I'm...
我在努力 我很快就会回家
I'm trying. I'm coming home soon.
- 欢迎来到麦当劳 - 麦当劳
- Welcome to McDonald's. - McDonald's!
孩子们 别激动 小点声
Guys, chill out! Turn it down!
别激动 妈妈在开车 好吗
Calm down. Mommy's driving. Okay?
我们要二十五份儿童套餐 谢谢
We'll take 25 Happy Meals, please!
不 我们不要二十五份儿童套餐
No, we don't want 25 Happy Meals.
先生 您能稍等一下吗
Sir, can you just hang on one more second?
我们要饿死了
We're so hungry!
我知道你们饿了 再等一下
I know you are. Just hold on.
可是我们想要玩具
But we want the toys.
随便帮我点六份吃的就行了
Just give me whatever you want. Six of whatever.
我这有六个饿着肚子的小孩
I've got six hungry kids.
- 我们不能这么做 - 装进外卖袋就行了
- We don't do that here. - Throw it all in there.
爸爸 我们要有小宝宝了
Daddy, we're having a baby!
- 什么 - 艾米莉
- What? - Oh, Emily!
贝基 她刚刚说什么了
Becky, what did she just say?
一个宝宝 我们要有小宝宝了
A baby. We're having a baby.
- 另一个宝宝 - 一个宝宝
- Another baby? - A baby.
您需要几份儿童套餐
How many Happy Meals did you want?
给我什么都行 无所谓
You can give me whatever you want! I don't care.
还要麦乐鸡块或芝士汉堡吗
Chicken McNuggets or cheeseburgers?
我们就要有妹妹了
We're having a sister!
不 这样就行了 谢谢
No, that's it, please.
此时在开罗的美国大使馆外
About 1,500 people gathered
已经聚集了约一千五百人...
outside the American Embassy here in Cairo...
家里有什么新消息吗
So, anything new back home?
此处指电影"穆斯林的无知"
...为表达他们对一部非正式
...to voice their discontent and anger
美国电影的不满与愤怒
about an American-made amateur film
他们觉得那是对先知穆罕穆德的侮辱
they say is insulting to the Prophet Muhammad.
没有吗
No?
什么都没有吗
Nothing?
和你聊天很开心
Good talk.
他们表示 虽然那是非正式的
They say that although it's amateur,
但仍侮辱了先知穆罕穆德
it is very much insulting
这已经触碰到了他们的底线
toward the prophet Muhammad and that is their red line.
你好
What up?
听说开罗的事了吗
Heard about Cairo?
"神话的力量" 作者: 约瑟夫·坎贝尔
启发启发我 布恩
Enlighten me, Boon.
"所有的神 天堂和地狱
"All the gods, all the heavens,all the hells
都在你的心中"
are within you."
- 在我心中 - 在你心中
- Within me? - Within you.
我会好好思考一下的
I might have to think about that one.
- 我整晚都会待在这里 - 好的
- Be here all night. - All right.
你知道 我房里真的有把枪 而且我会用它的
You know, I do have a gun in my cubby and I will use it.
一路顺风
Good luck.
她要去和她的联络人共进晚餐
She's having dinner with her contact.
我们会在晚上十点回来
We'll be back at 22:00.
是的
Yeah.
关于此事我仍在等待国务院的回应
Well, I'm still waiting to hear back from State on that.
听着 我只是想为今天的事情道歉
Hey, listen, I just wanted to say I'm sorry about today.
我不知道我当时在想什么
I don't know what I was thinking.
可能是在思考接下来的事情
I guess with what we got going on,
我只是希望一切都安好 你知道 我...
I just wanted everything to be right, you know. I...
我只希望别做错事 但是
I just wanted to do it right, but
我太高兴了 我
I'm so happy. I...
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我很想你们
I miss you guys very much.
我希望我能在家里
I wish I was home.
我真希望我能在家里
I just wish I was home.
小心敲掉你的牙
It'll knock your teeth out.
这些是上好的番石榴水烟
This is some good guava shisha.
我逮到你了
Yeah, I got you.
是从前门传来的吗
Is that the front gate?
妈的
Holy fuck!
快去拿武器
Go jock up!
- 我去找大使 - 我去管控中心
- I'm getting the Ambo! - I'll take the TOC!
跟上我 维尼 注意你的身后
Follow me, Vinnie! Watch your six.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
克利斯 快穿上防弹衣
Chris! Get your body armor on!
去安全屋 快
Get into the safe haven! Go!
快去
Go!
快点
Hurry!
我的天 到处都是他们的人
Oh, my God. They're everywhere.
我们该怎么办
What should we do?
M4卡宾枪在哪里
Where's the M4?
西恩
Sean!
戴夫 拿上你的武器然后赶去别墅
Dave, get your weapon and move fast to villa.
有多少人
How many?
从所有的监控看来 大约有三十
All DS be advised, there are thirty...
或者四十名敌人正在从查理一号门进来
...maybe 40 Tangos coming through the Charlie-1 gate.
有人吗
Hello?
它坏了 电话 我需要一个电话
It doesn't work. Phone! I need a phone!
亚力克 联系中情局 联系基地
Alec, call the CIA, call the annex!
全球反应人员 全员立刻到指挥室集合
GRS, all GRS, muster in the CP right now.
我还以为这会是个平静的夜晚
I thought it was gonna be a peaceful night.
领事馆遇袭了
State's under attack!
领事馆遇袭了 快走 兄弟
State's under attack! Let's go, man.
斯科特 你找到大使了吗
DS Scott, do you have hands on the Ambo yet?
正在把他人和客人送入安全屋
Moving package and guest in the safe haven.
进去躲着
Get down there.
不行 我需要更多的信息
No, I need more information than that.
情况如何 主管 有多少名敌人
What do we got, Chief? How many?
二十至四十名袭击者
Twenty to 40 attackers.
外交安全局的人分散在多个区域
State personnel separated in several positions.
那是什么
What's that?
我听见了自动步枪
I hear AKs.
火箭筒的声音
RPGs.
这可不妙
That's not good.
- 我该做什么 - 回去躲着
- What do I do? - Get back down!
我们得回去
We're going back.
外面什么情况
What's going on out there?
听着
Listen up.
你们都没必要去
None of you have to go.
但我们是他们唯一的希望
But we are the only help they have.
两辆车 准备就绪 出发吧 快走 快走
Two vehicles, staged and ready. Let's go! Move! Move!
他们进来了吗
Are they coming in?
天哪 根本没有可以藏身的地方
Jesus! There's nowhere to hide!
去别的房间 快 去别的房间
Get in the other room! Go! Get in the other room!
的黎波里
Tripoli?
的黎波里 班加西领事馆遇袭了
Tripoli, Benghazi is under attack.
大使在安全屋
The Ambo is in the safe haven.
我们被攻占了
We are overrun.
我们需要紧急援助
We need immediate assistance.
我们他妈的需要援助
We need some fucking help!
的黎波里  美国大使馆  距离班加西四百英里
穆罕穆德·马贾里亚夫 当时利比亚的临时元首
马贾里亚夫接电话了吗
Magariaf pick up the phone yet?
我联系上了华盛顿特区的指挥中心
I got Op Center at State in D.C.
美军九大联合作战司令部之一 负责美军在非洲领土的作战
美军非洲司令部已在线上
U.S. Military AFRICOM holding.
这里是美军非洲司令部
Yes, AFRICOM.
敌军已经开火 并在喊有口号
Firing and chanting.
前门被攻破 本地守卫逃走了
Front gate. Local guards ran.
二十至四十名敌人 战斗力很强
Twenty to 40 Tangos, that's a substantial force.
我们现在就得出发 主管
We got to go right now, Chief.
我们在领事馆没有权限
We have no authority at the consulate.
我们在这个国家没有管辖权
We have no jurisdiction in this country.
我们根本不该在这里
We're not supposed to be here.
但我们已经在这了
But we are here.
我们在与二月十七日旅合作
We're coordinating with 17 Feb.
他们会处理好的
They're gonna take the point.
绝对不行 现在一名美国大使身处险境
Absolutely not. You have a U.S. Ambassador at risk.
主管 派我们去 你必须派我们去
Send us, Chief. You've got to send us.
大使和他的保镖躲在安全屋
The Ambassador is in his safe haven with his body man.
你们不是第一救援力量
You're not the first responders.
你们是最后可依靠的力量
You're the last resort.
你们继续待命
You will wait.
我们在利比亚没有任何军事力量
We have no military assets in country.
我们在利比亚有两处辅助军事力量
We have two paramilitary assets in the country.
其中一处距领事馆只有一英里
One just a mile away from the Ambassador.
另一个呢
And the other?
给我一袋钱和一架去班加西的飞机
I need a bag full of money and a flight to Benghazi.
斯科特
Scott,
袭击者就在你们门外
there are Tangos right outside your door.
别妄动 别出声
Do not move. Do not make a sound.
- 阿莫尔 - 怎么了
- Amahl! - Yes?
如果要和二月十七旅联系的话
If we link up with 17 Feb,
我们没人会说阿拉伯语
none of us knows the language.
伙计 我们需要你 来吧
We need you, man. Come on.
什么 坦托 我不是战地翻译
Hey, hey, what? Tanto, I'm not a combat interpreter!
我甚至都没有持枪资格
I'm not weapons qualified.
- 这是什么 - 你现在有持枪资格了
- What is this? - Now you're qualified.
去戴头盔 穿防弹衣 我们走
Get your helmet and armor. Let's go.
这伙计不会回来了
That dude ain't coming back.
你这是在跟我耍花样吗
Are you actually trying to fuck me over?
不 我说的根本不是这个意思 等等
No, that's not what I'm saying at all. Just hold on!
听我说
Now, listen to me.
我们失去先机了 主管
Losing the initiative, Chief.
你能不能等一下
Will you just hold on?
你在贻误战机 你知道会有什么后果吗
You're losing it. You understand how that works?
待命 待命
Stand down. Stand down!
等我的指令
Wait for my word!
至少让我们派出侦察
At least let us get eyes on.
这样我们就能确定是否需要我们介入
Then we know if we have to intervene.
如果有埋伏 而你们中了圈套呢
And if there's an ambush and you get entrenched?
谁去救你们
Who rescues you?
我吗
Me?
奥兹 认真听我说
Oz, you need to listen to me very carefully,
现在离开
leave now.
不要接近大使馆
You don't go anywhere near the embassy.
抱歉打扰 我们得走了
Pardon the interruption. We need to go.
- 我们才刚开始吃晚餐 - 现在就走
- We've just started dinner. - Now.
见鬼 你们这些人 每次我就要...
Goddamn, you guys! Every time I get close...
戴上头巾
Put your head scarf on!
我需要你仔细看仔细听 不需要你说个没完
I need your eyes and your ears, not your mouth.
基地 领事馆遭到袭击
Annex, we have attackers on compound.
我们需要立即支援 我们遇袭了
We need immediate help. We are under attack.
德国  斯图加特  美军非洲司令部
集结所有可用特种作战单位
Spool up all available Special Ops.
我希望部队尽快出动
I want teams mobilized ASAP.
西格奈拉基地 位于意大利西西里岛
把他们部署到意大利西格奈拉海军航空基地
Stage them in Sigonella, Italy.
F16战斗机待命 等我指令
Have F16s ready on my command,
五分钟内给我关于所有军事力量的现况报告
and I want SITREP on all assets in 5 minutes.
我们的无人机将在四十六分钟后到达
We'll have eyes on station in 46 minutes.
进入其领空后 我们只有四十五秒停留时间
After ingress, we'll only have 0:45 overhead.
我们需要控制好飞行
We need to manage his flight.
美国军事侦察照相卫星
锁眼卫星提供近距空中支援
Keyhole tactics overhead for close air support.
华盛顿特区 美国五角大楼
我刚刚得知距领事馆一英里
I'm just learning we've got a classified CIA base
有个装满美国人的中情局秘密基地
a mile away full of Americans.
情况将向总统进行汇报
POTUS is about to be briefed.
门是防弹的 门是防弹的
It's bulletproof. It's bulletproof.
怎么样了
What's happening?
他们可能要撤走了
They might be going away.
斯科特 你能带大使上一辆装甲车吗
Scott, can you get the Ambo to an armored car?
走吧 我们他妈的得出发了
Let's go! We got to fucking move!
搞不好这就将是圣战的开始了
Could be the start of the Holy War.
你要穿着短裤参加圣战吗
You gonna fight the Holy War in your shorts?
勇气可嘉
Strong move.
我们到底在等什么
What the fuck are we waiting for?
我们在待命
We're holding.
他又在和二月十七日旅联系
He's going with Feb 17 again.
他不想暴露基地
He doesn't want to expose the annex.
真他妈的一团乱
Fucking mess.
那边简直像个烟火秀
It's like a damn fireworks show over there.
说真的 伙计们
Seriously, guys,
就算是领事馆订个披萨
if the consulate ordered a fucking pizza
这会也他妈该到了
it would've been there by now.
不是吧 妈的
No. Fuck you.
斯科特 他们在往屋内搬柴油桶
Scott, they are bringing diesel cans over to the villa.
斯科特 他们进去了
Scott, they are coming inside.
他们打算烧死你们
They're gonna burn you out.
好吧 好吧
Okay, okay.
爬到浴室去 去浴室
Get in the bathroom, crawl. Go to the bathroom, go!
他们挨着门泼了柴油
They are pouring the diesel right by the door.
不 不要
No, don't.
别他妈这么做
Don't you fucking do it.
别这样
Don't do it.
老天
Oh, God.
见鬼
Shit.
拿毛巾
Get the towels.
克利斯 防毒面具在哪
Chris, where are the gas masks?
天哪
Oh, God.
我无法呼吸了 我无法呼吸了
I can't breathe! I can't breathe!
烟太多了
It's too much smoke.
克利斯 跟我来 跟我来
Chris, follow me. Follow me.
的黎波里 美国大使馆
看看是否能联系上
See if you can get hold of
那个区域其他的快速反应部队
any other quick-reaction forces in the area.
是
Yes.
跟我来 跟我来
Follow me! Follow!
杰克 有多严重
Jack, how bad?
全球反应人员 你们在哪里
GRS, where are you guys?
请快来救救我们
Please help.
他们闯进去了 隆
They're digging in now, Rone.
我们需要空中支援
We need some air support.
即AC-130U空中炮艇 是一种由美国空军所操作的重型对地攻击机系统 主要用于空中支援与武装侦察等用途
一架幽灵攻击机 一架侦察无人机
A Spectre gunship, an ISR drone...
美国火力支援 伙计
American firepower, man.
我知道我们需要什么
I know what we need.
主管 主管
Chief! Chief!
已经过去二十分钟了
Twenty minutes now.
解救行动已成了自杀行动
It's going from a rescue mission to a suicide mission.
让我们去吧 现在性命攸关
Let us loose. Lives are at stake.
你们不是直接行动组
You are not direct-action elements.
主管 你好好想想
Chief, think.
你让他们占领了领事馆
You let them take that consulate,
你觉着他们的下一个目标会是哪
where do you think the next target's gonna be?
基地 我们需要救援
Annex, we need your help.
如果你们再不尽快来
If you do not get here soon,
我们就都他妈要死了
we are all gonna fucking die.
阿莫尔 上车 我们走
Amahl, get in the fucking car now. Let's go!
现在 我们走
Now! Let's go!
阿莫尔 站住 不准离开基地 阿莫尔
Amahl, stop! Do not leave this compound, Amahl.
上车 阿莫尔 我们走
Get in, Amahl. Let's go!
阿莫尔 我没批准你去
Amahl! You're not cleared to go!
见鬼 你们都是擅自行动
God damn it! None of you are!
这工作肯定没得干了
Say goodbye to contract work.
千金难换问心无愧
You can't put a price on being able to live with yourself.
的黎波里 我们需要紧急支援
Tripoli, we need immediate assistance.
我们现在他妈的需要帮助
We need fucking help now!
那些混蛋不会明白他们将要面对什么
These assholes have no idea what's coming for them.
见鬼 这他妈是在逗我吧
Shit. You got to be fucking kidding me.
我丢了隐形眼镜
I lost my contact.
见鬼 看不清东西我就没法去
Shit! I can't go if I can't see.
你得想办法解决 伙计
You got to fix this, man.
你得马上想办法解决
You got to fix this right now.
你这家伙 他妈的闭嘴
Hey, funny man, shut the fuck up.
你知道我们要去哪
You know where you're going.
- 这不好笑 - 等等
- This ain't funny. - Hold up.
二月十七日旅知道我们要来 对吧
Now 17 Feb knows we're coming, right?
我们怎么知道那是不是二月十七日旅的人
And how do we know that's 17 Feb?
隆 你看到了什么
Rone, what are you seeing?
我们距前门三百码 主管
We're 300 yards from the front gate, Chief,
但有一个路障
but there's a roadblock.
是友军吗 是二月十七日旅吗
Are they friendlies? Feb 17?
主管 我们正在确认
Chief, trying to assess,
但这里他妈的没人穿制服
but no one's wearing fucking uniforms here.
下来 下来
Come on. Come on.
我晚来可不是为了死在友军枪下的
I didn't get here late just to die in friendly fire.
用好你的枪
Use your gun.
问清楚他们指挥官是谁
Find out who the commander is
弄清楚局面 快去
and get this organized quick. Go.
去吧
Go.
停下
Stop!
阿莫尔 找掩护
Amahl, get cover!
- 主管 - 请救救我们
- Chief! - Please help.
叫主管来
Get the Chief!
- 他们走了吗 - 走了
- Are they gone? Yeah? - Yeah.
我让其他的工作人员都躲进了营房
I had the rest of the staff cover in their quarters.
好的 鲍勃 鲍勃 听我说
Okay, Bob, Bob, listen to me.
该行动由我全权指挥 好吗
I want 100% accountability. All right?
我们要加强C栋的安保
We're gonna harden our defenses here in C.
这将是我们最后的退路
This is gonna be our fallback.
封锁这栋大楼 你 还有你 跟我走
Hey, lock this building down! You, you, let's go. Let's go.
照做
Do it.
我能帮什么忙
How can I help?
美军联合特种作战部队 准备前往前线基地
意大利 阿维亚诺空军基地 美军F16战斗机快速反应部队
我们在向前推进
We're pushing forward.
继续 继续
Got to move, got to move.
前门有八到十个武装敌人
Eight to 10 Tangos, front gate.
有一半几率这些人会转而攻击我们
50/50 these guys turn on us
并把我们干掉
and end this now.
坦托 我们去高处
Tanto! Let's get up high.
隆
Rone!
这条路可以作关卡
This road's a chokepoint.
我们去找阻击点
We'll get established,
可以安全前进了就告诉你们
let you know when it's clear to advance.
我们去拿重武器 马上回来
We're getting our heavy weapons. Be back.
泰格 去找阿莫尔
Tig, get Amahl.
通知二月十七日旅封锁这条路
Tell 17 Feb to lock down this road.
不要放任何人进来 好吗
I don't want anybody coming over here, all right?
- 现在行动 - 收到
- Let's go! Now! - Roger that.
看看这家伙
Check this dude out.
幸亏是我们这边的
Lucky we got that guy on our side.
看看这两个人
Hey, check these guys.
- 你们是二月十七日旅的吗 - 是的
- You 17 Feb? - Yeah.
好了 跟我们走
Well, shit, come on, let's go.
我们四个人就是一个战斗小组了 伙计
Four guys is a fireteam, bro.
别从背后对我们放枪就行了
Just don't shoot us in the back.
斯科特
Scott!
克利斯 克利斯
Chris! Chris!
我无法呼吸了
I can't breathe.
克利斯
Chris!
敌人接近了
Tango approaching.
坦托 回来 我们得前进了
Tanto, get back. We gotta move.
前方发现敌人
Contact, front!
注意火箭筒
RPG.
飞过来了
Incoming!
见鬼
Oh, shit!
找掩护 找掩护
Get cover, get cover!
向右前进 向右前进
Move right, move right!
左边 树旁边
Left! By the trees!
泰 右边
Ty, to the right!
走走走
Move, move, move!
- 坦托 走 - 快 快 快速前进
- Tanto, move. - Go, go, hustle!
我们正向前门推进
We're pushing forward to the front gate.
你们也许想进去看看
Might want to get inside.
美国橄榄球队
不知道他们能不能收看野马队的比赛
Wonder if they can get the Broncos game?
上去 上去
Get high, get high.
年纪大了爬不动墙了
I'm too fucking old to be climbing walls.
快点
Come on.
天哪 别拿枪指着我的脸 伙计
Jesus Christ, get your gun out of my face, bro. Fuck!
业余水平真见鬼
Fucking amateur hour, man.
他在里面吗 大使在不在里面
Is he inside? Is the Ambo inside?
西恩在里面吗 斯科特 好好想想
Is Sean inside? Scott, think.
你最后一次见到他是在哪里
Where did you see him last?
我们上屋顶 我们走
Let's get to the top of this building. Let's go!
从这里我们能穿到更高的建筑物那去
Up here we can cross over to the bigger building.
伙计们 我需要你们尽快找到狙击点
Guys, I need your eyes quick.
收到 隆 我们正以最快速度前进
Copy that, Rone. We are coming as fast as we can.
等等 我看到四个持枪敌人
Easy. I got four Tangos.
这他妈的是什么人
Who the fuck are these guys?
你们是美国人吗
You are Americans?
是的
Yes.
这些人在看足球赛
These guys are watching a soccer game.
又一个平凡的班加西周二之夜
Just another Tuesday night in Benghazi.
我们需要狙击手尽快就位进行掩护
We need sniper over-watch fast.
你们得快点
You got to move it!
视线被建筑物挡住了
We're blocked by buildings.
找不到狙击点
We got no vantage point.
见鬼
Fuck.
隆 这个地方不行 我们要继续前进
Rone, this roost is a bust. We're gonna keep moving.
我们正在向前门推进
Making our way to the front gate.
二月十七日旅和我们在一起
Feb 17 is rolling with us.
注意左边的那些人
Check those guys on the left.
泰格 武装皮卡 把那辆车打掉
Tig, technical! Knock out that technical!
泰格 你必须立刻
Tig, you got to knock out that
把那辆武装皮卡干掉
technical right fucking now, man!
泰格 端掉那辆武装皮卡 不然我们死定了
Tig, drop that technical or we're dead!
前进 前进 前进
Move, move, move!
隆 我们目前跑了大概一英里了
Rone, we've been running about a mile so far.
快要绕到领事馆后门了
Making it around to the back gate of the compound.
从卫星定位上 我们的人在哪里
On the GPS, where are our teams?
他们应该是走后面这条路
They should be coming back this way.
你看 他们就在这里
Look, they're right here.
坦托和布恩在后面这条路上
Tanto and Boon are on Gunfighter Road at the back.
隆的队伍快要从前门进去了
Rone's team is about to enter the front gate.
你好 美国队长 我在为我的祖国而战
Hello, Captain America. I'm fighting for my country.
欢迎
You're welcome.
看来我们要进去了
Guess we're going in.
外安局的 我们进入领事馆了
State, we're on property!
外安局的 我们进来了 进入领事馆了
State, we're coming in! We're on property!
美国 掠食者无人机 - 利比亚领空
三角洲掠食者无人机就位
Delta Pred checking in on station.
两分钟内可传回侦察画面
We'll have eyes on in two minutes.
快告诉我 他们在哪
Hey, talk to me, guys. Where are they?
我找遍了 找不到他们
I looked everywhere. I can't find them.
我想他们还在里面
I think they're still in there.
里面有敌人吗
You got bad guys inside?
我们走散了 我找不到他们
We got separated. I can't find them.
- 有几个我们的人 - 两个
- Our guys? How many? - Two.
我的天
God!
里面温度太高 从那边进 那个房间
It's too hot! Go around that way. That room.
- 那边吗 - 那边
- Over here? - There.
克利斯 见鬼
Chris! Shit.
杰克 过来
Jack, come here!
我们一起进
Let's go in.
准备好了 好的 进
Ready? Okay, go in.
- 克利斯 - 出去 出去
- Chris! - Let's go, let's go, let's go!
没人能在里面活下来
No one could survive that.
我们走
Let's go.
- 大使 - 克利斯·史蒂文斯
- Ambo! - Chris Stevens!
- 大使 - 克利斯
- Ambo! - Chris!
- 克利斯 - 克利斯
- Chris! - Chris!
见鬼 我得多做些有氧运动了
Shit, I got to do more cardio.
袭击者应该会从这边出来
Should be bad guys coming out here.
也许他们已经出来了
Maybe they already came through.
摄像头就位
Phantom Cyclops.
领事馆后门处发现两名友军
I have two friendlies, IR strobed,
美军有红外发射模块 方便己方辨识
红外识别闪烁
back gate of the compound.
我们要从后门进去 不要开枪
Hey, we are coming over the back gate. Do not shoot.
刚才经过咖啡馆看到的那些人
Hey, those guys we just passed at the cafe?
是我们这边的吗
Are they with us?
- 友军吗 - 不 长官 不是
- Friendlies? - No, mister, no.
我们要翻墙过去
We're going over the wall.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
如果他们向我们开枪...
If they shoot at us...
是 长官
Yes, sir.
- 你就杀了他们 - 是 长官
- you kill them. - Okay, mister. Okay.
克利斯
Chris!
天哪
God!
克利斯
Chris!
克利斯·史蒂文斯
Chris Stevens!
坦托 这外面就跟街头聚会一样
Tanto, it's like a goddamn block party out here.
到里面来 伙计
Get in here, dude.
你们是二月十七日旅的吗
You 17 Feb?
- 我是指挥官 - 太好了
- I'm a commander. - Good for you.
等你们人都进去以后
Once you get all your guys through here,
就把这个门关紧 明白吗
you got to close this gate, okay?
- 可以 没问题 - 好
- Okay? All right. - Okay.
等下 你在跟谁说话
Wait. Who are you talking to?
你给谁打电话
Who's on the phone?
好的
Okay.
我打给袭击者 也许能说服他们投降
I call attackers. Maybe I negotiate surrender.
等等 你打给袭击者
Wait. You called the attackers?
你竟然有他们电话
You have their phone...
你他妈的怎么会有他们电话
How the fuck do you have their phone number?
我现在是好人没错
I now a good boy.
但也认识很多坏人
But I know bad guys.
- 搞什么 - 坦托 进来 需要你支援
- What? - Tanto, get in here. We need you.
知道了伙计 马上来
Yeah, dude, I know, I know, I'm coming.
跟着我的声音
Follow my voice!
杰克 继续说话
Jack, keep talking!
泰 跟着我的声音走
Ty, follow my voice!
- 好 你在哪里 - 跟着我的声音
- Okay. Where are you? - Follow my voice!
杰克 杰克 我什么都看不见
Jack! Jack, I can't see!
泰
Ty!
走 快出去
Go, go, go.
阿莫尔
Amahl!
我带来了十七日旅的人
Hey, I brought these 17 guys, okay?
但我真觉得这些混蛋
But I do think these assholes,
想偷我们的车
they were trying to steal our cars.
这些人本该负责前哨的
They were the dudes who were supposed to take point.
没错
Yeah.
现在这状况实在是太糟了
Now, this is fucking bad.
隆 我们在院子后面
Rone, we're in the back of the compound,
准备进入管控中心
we're going to the TOC.
该死的
Oh, shit.
我的天 那房子被点燃了
Jesus Christ, that shit is torched.
这些人是谁
Who are these guys?
大兵 美国人有麻烦了
Solider! Americans are in trouble!
啥
Huh?
你们美国人遇到麻烦了
Your Americans are in trouble!
走 快走
Go, go, go. Go!
快走
Go, go, go.
这是谁
Who is it?
西恩·史密斯 我们的信息技术员
It's Sean Smith, our IT guy.
走 把他抬起来
Let's go. Hold him up.
泰格 医疗袋拿过来
Tig, med bag!
我刚才还跟他在一起
I was just with him.
刚才还在一起
全球反应人员正向管控中心前进
GRS moving in on the TOC.
我们在管控中心外面
Hey, we're outside the TOC.
门锁上了 里面有人吗
Door's locked. Anybody in there? Over.
行了 他死了
That's it. He's gone.
- 他死了 - 不
- He's gone. - No!
他已经死了
He's gone.
现在不是难过的时候 振作点
Now is not the time. Get yourself together.
- 泰格 - 不
- Tig. - No.
别浪费精力了 他已经死了
Don't waste your energy, man. He's gone.
杰克 来把他抬上车
Jack, let's get his body in the vehicle.
抬起来
Pick him up.
好了 走
All right, move.
告诉我这叫哪门子友军
Explain to me how all these guys are friendlies.
很好笑 我也不明白
Funny, I don't know.
好笑 一点都不好笑
Funny? It's not that funny.
你是什么人
Who are you?
忽然从草丛里
What are you doing,
跳出来 你想干嘛
coming out of the bushes like that?
管控中心里的人 能看见我们吗
Hey, inside the TOC, do you see us?
我们要进去
We need to come in.
你知道最初的袭击只是为了
You know that thing where the initial assault
吸引其它人
is just a ploy to
加入真正袭击的手段吧
draw people in for the real attack?
神啊
Jesus Christ.
快开门 不然我就炸门了
Open your door or I'm gonna fucking blow it open!
友军
Blue.
我们是中央情报局的
CIA!
嘿
Whoa! Hey!
放松 阿甘 我们需要你
Easy, Forrest Gump! We need you.
里面还有人吗
Is there anybody else inside?
没了
No, no.
- 多亏有你 兄弟 - 没事 伙计
- Glad you're here, brother. - Yeah, buddy.
嘿 他们又回来了
Hey. Hey. They're coming back!
据说袭击者正在重新集结
They said the attackers are regrouping,
援军增加了
adding reinforcements.
回来赶尽杀绝吗
Coming back to finish the job?
杰克 去管控中心帮忙把机密文件拿出来
Jack, help get State's classifieds out of the TOC.
我带外交安全局的人离开这里
I'm gonna get DS out of here.
你们最好快点
You better hurry up.
阿莫尔 跟我来 走
Amahl, follow me. Let's go.
坦托 有麻烦要来了
Tanto, we got a situation coming our way.
外交安全局的人 上车
DS! Get in your car.
坦托 是友军
Tanto, blue, blue!
布恩在里面 进去吧
Boon's inside. Go.
杰克 那边什么情况
Jack, what's going on over there?
不怎么乐观
It's not good.
一人死亡 还有人躲在草丛里
We got one KIA. We got guys still in the bushes.
没找到大使
No Ambo.
袭击者还没走
They're still here.
我觉得到处都是敌人
I think we got hostiles everywhere.
火势刚好能做掩护
The fire has just got to be cover.
他们已经控制了整个院落
They have control of the compound.
为什么要这么快撤退
Why else leave so fast?
想想《黑鹰坠落》 伙计
Black Hawk Down, man.
他们会把他的尸体拖到街上游行
They're gonna drag his body through the streets.
阿莫尔 嘿
Amahl. Hey.
阿莫尔 振作点
Amahl, pull it together, man. Come on.
过来 别拿着枪乱指
Come here. Stop pointing your gun!
准备好了吗
We ready?
都在我这了 走吧
On me. Here we go.
走吧 阿莫尔 出去
Let's go. Amahl, out.
该死的 这个混蛋杂种
Oh! Goddamn it! This cockbag motherfucker!
注意 二月十七日旅的天才指挥官
Be advised the 17 Feb tactical genius commander
他妈的把后门大开着
left the back gate wide fucking open.
好吧 布恩 这面墙做为新的防线
All right, Boon, this wall set as new perimeter.
用作掩护 拖延敌人
Take cover, hold it.
我们把外交安全局的人带出去
We're getting DS out of here.
走 行动
Let's go! Move!
请到里面去 回到里面去
Go inside, please. Go back inside.
马上进屋子里 去屋子里
Get in the house right now! In the house!
全部处理掉 什么都不留
Fire sale! Everything must go.
一大波敌人正朝我们这来
We got a large group of bad guys headed our way.
我们留在这寻找大使下落
We're gonna stay and look for the Ambo.
你们先撤退
You guys need to exfil.
我们少两个人
We're short two guys.
我这多出来两个特工 但我们得待在一起
I got two more agents, and I'm not leaving them.
坦托 现在什么状况 我们得走了
Hey, Tanto, what's going on, man? We got to move.
蠢货
You dumb piece of shit!
你们想搞自杀式袭击吗
You blew yourself up trying to frag us, huh?
二月十七日旅的
17 Feb?
是
Yes!
该死的
Fuck.
见鬼
Oh, shit!
布恩 我们退回去
Boon! Let's go back!
杰克 注意我们的背后
Jack, watch our six!
听我说 听我说
All right. Listen to me. Listen, hey. Listen up!
出大门以后左拐
When you go outside that gate, you go left,
明白吗
you understand?
- 明白 - 真的明白
- Yes. - You understand?
抓紧时间
Haul ass!
嘿 快点
Hey! Hey! Hurry up!
我们走 快快快
Let's go! Let's go! Move, move, move!
快走
Let's move!
右边都是敌人 你要朝左拐
To the right is bad guys. You are going left.
从基地的后面进去
You're taking the back way to the annex.
- 懂了吗 - 懂了
- You got it? - I got it.
听着 我觉得换个人开车好点
Listen, I think somebody else should drive.
不 我能开
No, I'm driving!
是友军
Blue! Blue!
别开枪
No, don't shoot!
走走走
Move, move, move, move.
第二波袭击来了
Second wave is coming!
敌人正从后门涌进来
They're flooding in through the back gate!
快跑 快跑
Peel it! Peel it! Peel it!
得有人在屋顶做掩护
Someone cover us on the roof!
阿莫尔 跟着泰格 我们把这些人赶出去
Amahl, on Tig! Let's get these guys out.
我去屋顶 别把我留下了
I'm on the roof. Don't leave me.
呼叫国务院 我们正在撤离领事馆
State. We are exfilling the compound,
没找到大使
minus the Ambo.
不对 不对 他说了朝左拐
No, no, no, he said go left.
朝左
Left!
- 斯科特 左拐 - 不对 他说右拐
- Scott, left. - No, he said right.
退回去走另一边
Go back the other way.
- 嘿 闪开 - 退回去
- Hey, get out of the way! - Back right.
左拐 朝左拐
Left! Go left!
快走 快走
Go! Go!
走 走
Move, move, move.
这家伙是什么人
Who's this fucking guy?
不知道 可能是十七日旅的
I don't know. Maybe he's 17 Feb.
也许是友军
Maybe he's friendly.
也许他是在说
Maybe he's saying go the other way.
走另一边
Go the other way.
不对 左拐
No! Left!
朝左拐 左拐
Go left! Go left! Left!
真不敢相信我们没找到大使就走了
I can't believe we left without him.
你走错路了
You're going the wrong way.
杰克 到屋顶上来
Jack, get up here on roof.
泰格 我在你右边
Tig, on your right.
下面路上 后门那里
Down road, back gate.
敌人在左边
Tangos left.
这帮人不可能在这待一整晚
Hey. No way these guys are in for the night.
他们初尝胜利的果实
They got a little taste of victory.
下个目标就是基地
The annex is next.
坦托 布恩 集合 我们离开这里
Tanto, Boon, consolidate. Let's get the fuck out of here.
走吧
Let's go!
撤退
Exfil!
把门打开
Get that door open!
刚才真是激烈
That was intense.
我忘了榴弹发射器了
I forgot the grenade launcher.
有一辆车在移动
We got a mover.
外安局的装甲车正在离开使馆区
State armored car leaving compound.
捕捉到目标车辆 顺发射中心22度角
Target vehicle intercept. Downrange 22 degrees.
一切就绪 等待命令
Stand by for words.
我们在绕圈 斯科特
We just went in a circle, Scott.
什么情况
What is this shit?
这人是谁
Who is this?
他在说什么
What is he saying?
不太妙 快走吧
This is a bad idea. Just go.
目标车辆停下来了
Target vehicle has stopped.
敌人从四面八方汇聚过来
Tangos converging from all sides.
这人是谁 这是谁
Who the fuck is this guy? Who is this guy?
你是什么人
Who are you?
他这个动作
He's doing this.
可能想说他不是敌人
I think he's trying to say he's friendly.
不 我们不认识这些人 这很危险
No, we don't know these guys. This is not safe.
我们不认识他们 待在这很危险
We don't know them. We're not safe here.
阳台上有两个人 阳台上有两个人
Two guys on the balcony. Two guys on the balcony.
我们得离开这里
We need to get out of here.
那是谁
Who is that?
这是陷阱 戴夫 肯定有埋伏
It's a trap, Dave, it's an ambush!
我们得赶快走
We've got to move!
也可能他想阻止我们中埋伏
He might be trying to keep us from an ambush.
你是什么人
Who are you?
快后退 快后退
Back up while we can. Back up while we can.
你们是谁
Who are you?
走开 别挡路
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
快走 快走 冲过去
Go, go, go! Push through!
继续开 继续开
Keep going! Keep going! Keep going!
走右边 右边
Go to the right! Go to the right! Go right! Go right!
该死的
Damn it.
直接轧过去
Run them the fuck over!
我们后面跟着三辆车 速度很快
We've got three cars coming up on our ass fast!
撞过去
Punch it, punch it!
小型火力正在朝目标车辆射击
Light fire pursuit of target vehicle
距离基地南边还有一半路程
half-click south of annex.
呼叫国务院 我们受到猛烈攻击 车胎瘪了
State. We're under heavy fire! We're on run-flats!
八点钟方向追上来一把AK
AK coming up eight o'clock!
这车窗可顶不住
This window's not gonna hold!
打死那个混蛋
Shoot that son of a bitch!
打死他
Shoot him!
是火箭筒
RPG!
飞过来了
Coming in!
冷静 隆 混入车群
Hey, easy, Rone. Try to blend.
我们是在车群中
We are.
后面装着一具尸体
With a dead body in the back,
车上坐着一帮全副武装的人
bunch of heavily armed operators
正准备回中情局基地藏身
just going back to hide in our covert CIA base.
有辆车跟着我们
Hey, we got a tail.
有两辆
Two of them.
呼叫基地 我们被跟踪了 有两到三辆车
Annex, we got a tail. Two or three vehicles in pursuit.
启动销毁程序 准备撤离
Start the destruction phase. Plan to evacuate.
穿过去 隆
Hit it, Rone.
怎么样了
How we looking?
- 甩掉了 隆 - 甩掉了 很棒
- You lost them, Rone. - You lost them. You're good.
- 确定吗 - 确定
- You sure? - Yep. Yep.
因为他知道我们基地的位置
That's because he knows where we live.
守卫 都进去塔楼里
Guard, get in the tower!
主厨 你准备好参加战斗了吗
Chef, you ready to get in the fight?
今晚不管谁闯进来
Anyone comes over these walls tonight,
都打得他屁滚尿流
we're kicking some ass.
继续前进 前进
Keep moving. Keep moving.
联系后门的人 快走
Contact rear! Go, go, go, go!
我们快到基地了
We're coming in hot.
距基地还有大概一百米
We're closing in at about 100 meters.
好了 关门
Let's go! Shut the gate!
嘿 回去 马上回去
Hey! Hey, get back inside! Get back! Now!
回里面去
Go back inside.
维尼 帮个忙 带他去医务室
Vinnie, give me a hand. Let's get him to medical.
去吧 带着他
Go. Take him.
你需要治疗吗
Does that need attention?
不不 我没事 轻伤而已
No, no. I'm good. It's a flesh wound.
我可以帮忙
Let me do something to help.
东边需要人手 去守D楼
I need men east side. Take Building D.
我们需要动用所有的人手 走吧
We need all the help we can get. Let's go.
你们在大门边吗 开门
You guys got the gate? Gate!
我已经把多余的弹药都带到楼顶上了
Hey. I had extra ammo brought up to the rooftops.
利比亚的卫兵都安排在了塔楼里
Libyan guards are positioned in the towers.
你们应该朝左拐的
Should've turned left.
去喝点水 补充弹药
Get some water and reload!
谁抬他进去
Who's gonna bring him inside?
他留在这就可以了 主管
He stays right here, Chief.
这样撤离的时候 速度更快
When we exfil out, it's gonna be quick.
大使怎么样了
What about the Ambassador?
那种情况谁都活不了
No one could survive that.
现在 楼顶上需要人手
Right now, we need men on the roof.
我想撤离到机场
I want to make a run for the airport.
你可能没注意到
Maybe you haven't noticed
现在班加西正处于自由猎杀美国人时期
it's open season on Americans in Benghazi right now.
隆
Rone.
所有弹匣都装满子弹了
Every extra mag loaded now.
盯好外面的监视器
Don't take your eyes off the exterior cameras.
隆 你知道如果我们继续留在这就死定了
Rone, you realize if we stay here that we are screwed.
那你怎么不找人支援我们 鲍勃
Then why don't you get us some fucking help, Bob?
告诉非洲司令部
Tell AFRICOM
你是从秘密基地打来的电话
you're calling from that classified base
就是他们一小时前才知道的那个基地
they didn't know existed until an hour ago.
你要明确要求
You be very specific.
要一架幽灵攻击机和无人侦察机
You get a Spectre gunship and an ISR Pred.
现在我们头上就有一架德尔纳市来的无人机
There is a drone from Derna overhead right now.
攻击机超出了航程范围
The gunship is out of fueling range.
他们是这样告诉我的
That's what they're telling me.
我正在下令撤离
I'm ordering the evacuation.
不再由你发号施令了
You're not giving orders anymore,
你服从命令
you're taking them.
现在你听我的
You're in my world now.
我试图找过他
I... I tried to find him.
没有攻击机吗
No gunship?
离黎明还有六个小时
Six hours till dawn.
整个城市都知道我们藏在哪
Entire city knows where we're holed up.
他们来的话
When they come,
就等着承受我们的怒火吧
we're gonna unleash hate on these guys.
先整理一下优先事项
Let's set our priorities.
应急预案
硬盘
文件
机密情报
我们继续执行基地销毁程序
We're gonna continue our base destruction protocol
直到销毁完毕
until it is finished.
我们会在三十到四十分钟之内撤离这里
We're gonna exfil from here in 30 to 40 minutes.
直接去机场
We're gonna go directly to the airport
找架飞机
and get a plane.
如果行不通的话
If that doesn't work,
那我们就去港口
we're gonna go to the port
直接偷一条船
and we're gonna steal a fucking boat.
无论何时 如果你们之中
If any one of you gets separated
有人脱离了队伍
from the group at any time,
记住这个号码
memorize this number.
美国中情局的卫星会定位
The CIA satellites will pick you up
你的地理位置
where you are located.
如果有人在本地友方民兵中有熟人
If there's anyone who has local assets with friendly militias,
请举手
raise your hands.
你们必须向我保证他们不会攻击我们
You need to assure me that those people are safe.
并且能护送我们离开这里
They're gonna secure our exit and escort us out of here.
现在就联系他们 马上
Call them right now, immediately.
所有部门的负责人过来
I want all heads of department over here.
给我弄间作战室
And I want a fucking war room.
我们要制定自己的计划
We're gonna make our finalized plans.
先听我说 你们接受过专业训练
Now, listen, listen. You're trained to do this.
这是你们的本职 你们能做到
It's your job. You can do it.
每个人都要为自己的生命负责
We're all responsible for our lives,
现在 你们在这间房里所做的事
and what you do right now in this room
将决定我们最后是死是生
will determine whether we live or die.
凌晨 12:06  的黎波里机场
相距四百英里
呼叫的黎波里 我们到了
Tripoli, we're here,
准备上石油公司总裁的喷气式飞机
getting on the oil executive's jet.
全球响应人员安全返回了
GRS is back safe.
领事馆被攻陷 还是没有大使的踪影
Compound's lost. Still no sign of the Ambo.
政府已经怪罪到伊斯兰教组织的头上了
State's already blaming Al-Sharia.
你是三角洲部队的 怎么 就你们两个人
You're Delta? What, just two of you?
就是我们了 兄弟
We're it, brother.
好吧
Okay.
糟糕透了
That sucks.
那就是我们的飞机 出发
There's our bird! Let's move.
非洲司令部
的黎波里
大使馆
非洲司令部
这应该是个电话号码 但它不是
That's supposed to be a phone number, and it's not.
你现在就得翻译出来
You need to translate this right now.
这些你拿到了吗
Did you get these?
销毁那些东西
Destroy those.
听着 听着 我听不清你说什么
Listen, listen! I'm having trouble hearing you,
但我们的线人正在搜索每间医院了
but our sources are checking every hospital.
美国国务院
兰利 中情局总部
你把情况报告给五角大楼和中情局了吗
Have you alerted the Pentagon and CIA?
是不是他们在讲话
Are they talking?
阿莫尔
Amahl!
阿莫尔 你看到了什么 你受伤了吗
Amahl, what did you see? Are you hurt?
阿莫尔 外面出了什么事
Amahl, what's happening out there?
- 太糟了 非常不好 - 阿莫尔
- It's so bad. It's not good. - Amahl!
阿莫尔 我能拿回我的枪么
Amahl, can I get my gun?
对不起 伙计 我可能会用到它
Sorry, buddy, I think I'm gonna need it.
见鬼
Shit.
外面情况怎么样
What's the situation out there?
拿支枪 去楼顶找我
Grab a gun, meet me on the roof.
我就告诉你
I'll tell you all about it.
他开玩笑的 是吧
He isn't serious, is he?
那是他干的活 不是我的
'Cause that's his job, that's not my job.
他是认真的
He is serious.
快上来 自己去看看
Come on up! Check it out!
听好了 伙计们
Listen up, guys!
我去C栋
I'm gonna take Building C.
杰克 泰格 你们去D栋
Jack, Tig, I want you on Building D.
坦托和布恩去A栋
Building A, Tanto, Boon.
外交安全局的人 B楼归你们
Building B, DS guys, that's your territory.
奥兹去一号塔 负责僵尸之地
Oz, Tower 1. Zombieland.
开始行动 各就各位
Let's go. Hit it.
快点
Move!
快快快 都加快速度
Let's go! Let's go! Let's hustle up!
隆 我到塔楼了 准备上C栋
Rone, I got the tower! Getting up on C!
他们只是本地的牧羊人
They're just the local shepherds.
嘿 怎么了
Hey, what's going on?
门口有个邻居过来
We got a neighbor at the gate
投诉我们的灯太亮了
complaining about our lights.
什么 他是不是以为我们要开泳池派对
What, does he think we're having a pool party?
他说不要开灯 不然他们会找到你们
He says the lights are bad. They're going to find you.
"他们"
"They"?
他怎么知道"他们"是谁 问他
How the fuck does he know who "They" Are? Ask him.
他已经走了
He's already gone.
兄弟们 我们要想想办法
Guys, we really need to do something
搞定这些灯
about these lights.
我们得把灯全都关掉
We've got to shut all these lights down.
兄弟们 让你们的红外线不停发信号给攻击机
Hey, guys, keep your IRS pointed up for the gunship
希望攻击机他妈地能来
that's hopefully fucking coming.
不用秘密行动了
Time for stealth has passed.
韦佩尔 把外缘的探照灯开着
Viper, keep the perimeter floodlights on.
关了里面的灯
Shut off the interiors.
收到 收到 快点 快翻到
Roger that. Roger that. Come on, come on.
在伊拉克时
In Iraq,
有黑鹰直升机救我们
we had Black Hawks to get us out of shit like this.
在这里我们什么都没有 也没有支援
Yeah. Well, here we got nothing and no one.
把里面的灯关掉
Kill the interior lights!
亮着灯我们就是活靶子
We're lit fucking targets up here.
我在关了 伙计
I'm trying, man.
你好啊
Hello.
真诡异
Surreal.
不在同一个世界
Different world.
这是谁
Who's this?
阿莫尔 那些车是
Amahl, are those cars
从邻居家里出来的吗
coming from the neighbor's house?
嘿 他们他妈的要去哪
Hey! Where the fuck are they going?
伙计们 我们刚刚失去所有的利比亚安全部队
Guys, we just lost all our Libyan security.
好像除了我们
Does it seem like everybody knows
每个人都知道是怎么回事
what's going on around here but us?
确实如此
That's for sure.
频闪信号灯开了 告诉无人机我们的位置
Strobe's on, marking our position for the Predator.
我不想打击你
I hate to break it to you,
但我认为不会有攻击机支援了
but I don't think we're getting any gunships.
鬼才会来 空中支援 那就简单多了
Oh. Hell no. Air support? That'd be too easy.
韦佩尔 把里面的灯都他妈给我关掉
Viper, turn off these goddamn interiors
不然我就自己打掉它们
or I'm gonna shoot them out myself!
我在关了
I'm working on it.
- 他今晚没睡好 - 给力啊
- He's having a bad night. - Work with me.
- 妈的 - 拜托
- Fuck. - Come on.
对不起 伙计们 我只是有点紧张
Sorry, guys. I'm just a bit nervous.
终于关了 谢谢
Wow. Thank you.
隆 你觉得他们会从哪条路进攻
Rone, which way you think they're coming?
他们来的话 肯定是从僵尸之地过来
When they come, they're coming through Zombieland.
很奇怪
That's strange.
那辆警车减速了 然后速度又加回去了
That cop slowed down, then sped back up.
我觉得我他妈置身在恐怖片中
I feel like I'm in a fucking horror movie.
- 大厨 - 怎么了
- Chef? - Yeah?
就放在那里行了
Put that down right there.
你去楼下 确保楼里每个人都安全
You go downstairs, make sure everybody in this building's safe.
这就去
Got it.
奥兹 这就是我们表明立场的地方
Oz? This is where we make our stand!
- 外面很黑 - 嘿 隆
- It's dark out there. - Hey, Rone,
我们准备去B栋 那边位置更有利
We're going to Building B. It's better vantage.
叫外交安全局的人离开那里
Get those DS guys off of there.
外安局的
State!
你们下楼
I want you to go down
在地面保护C栋
and protect Building C from the ground.
伙计们 我们要让射击区域
Guys, let's set sectors of fire with
相互重叠
overlapping coverage.
泰格 我在三号塔上和你范围相同
Tig, I can use you over here on Tower 3.
奥兹 有什么发现吗
Oz, what do you got?
只有几个本地牧羊人在散步
I got a couple of local shepherds walking.
嘿 我们负责这里 外面空地面积太大
Hey, State, we got this. Lot of acreage out there.
- 戴上你们的夜视镜 - 收到
- Get on your NODs. - Copy that.
主管 我们在等任何友军
Hey, Chief. Are we expecting
来设置外围防线吗
any friendlies to set up a perimeter?
我印象里没有 怎么了
Not that I know of. Why?
因为我们的东侧聚集了很多车
'Cause we got cars amassing, east side.
就在那栋房子外面的停车场
In the parking lot out by that house
还有几个青少年在院子里放炮仗
where the teenagers are that throw the M-80s over the yard.
所以我猜他们要打牌玩通宵了
Then I guess it could be poker night.
你等等
Just hold on.
我看到有两辆警车开了进去
Hey. I got two cop cars pulling in.
主管 我们近期在等
Chief, are we expecting
班加西的警方来支援吗
any of Benghazi's finest anytime soon?
我核实一下 等等
Let me check on it. Hold on.
你慢慢来
Yeah. Take your time.
艾伦 看下外围的情况
Alan, check the perimeter.
打电话问班加西警方是否有派人来
Call Benghazi police and see if that's them.
主管 这些警察
Chief, these cops?
我赌他们和坏人是一伙的
I bet you they work for the bad guys.
你觉得这像二月十七日旅的人吗
Does this look like 17 Feb to you?
老兄 你他妈怎么知道
Dude, how can you fucking tell?
在证明他们不是敌人之前 他们都是敌人
They're all bad guys until they're not.
警车走了
And there go the cop cars.
我这边有动静 你们看到了吗
I got movement. You see this, guys?
我看到了
Yeah, I see it.
布恩 你看到多少个人
Boon, how many you see?
人数不清 他们正在向停车场移动
I got unknowns moving to the parking lot.
十五个目标
Fifteen Tangos.
我等下给你回电话
I gotta call you back.
这个制高点真的不错
Good vantage point from here.
奥兹
Oz?
我这边有超过五个人
All right. I got five more guys
就跟在小牧羊人的后面
right behind them little shepherds.
有一个人斜背着什么东西
One of them's got something slung.
我看不清是什么
I can't see what it is.
班加西的人都有武器
Everyone's got weapons in Benghazi.
除非你看到某人手上有武器
Until you see a weapon in someone's hands,
否则不要开枪
you do not fire.
我不想有人因此蹲大牢
I don't want anybody going to prison.
收到
Roger that.
现在他们分散了 游戏时间到
Okay, they're breaking off. It's game time.
兄弟们 他们来了
Guys, they are coming in.
没错 他们现在过来了
Oh, yeah, they're coming in now. Come on.
主管 如果我们在等任何友军的话
Chief, if we're expecting any friendlies,
我现在就要知道
I need to know that information now.
我不知道有什么友军
I am not aware of any friendlies.
我未收到确认
I have no confirmation.
非洲司令部 根据部署的频闪追踪器
AFRICOM, ISR is approaching target coordinates
无人侦察机正在接近目标地点
from deployed strobe tracker.
等候下一步指令
Await further instruction.
无人机 报告侦察情况
ISR, eyes-on report.
非洲司令部 若干身份不明的人
AFRICOM, unknowns are advancing
正穿过南方和东南方的空地
toward subject compound
向目标院落前进
moving from south/southeast over open ground.
没有标志或军旗 行动分散
No tags or colors. Asymmetrical movements.
没有观测到武器
No weapons observed.
摄像机放大倍数达到一百四十
Cyclops pushing in at 140.
我们现在已经被敌人包围了
State, we're being surrounded by Tangos right now.
主管 恶梦要开始变成现实了
Chief, this shit's starting to get real.
奥兹 柱子附近有七个敌人
Oz, we got seven Tangos by the pillars.
看到了
Got 'em.
让他们过来
Let 'em come.
让他们来
主管 能批准射击了吗
Chief, are we cleared hot to shoot?
主管 我再问一遍 能批准射击了吗
Chief, I repeat, are we cleared hot to shoot?
看到武器后 狙击手自行判断射击
See a weapon, shooter's discretion.
都不要开枪
Everybody hold.
没有我的命令都他妈不准开枪
You do not fucking fire till I give the word.
布恩 我不会射小孩子的
I ain't shooting no kids, Boon.
好了 伙计们 睁大双眼
All right, guys, eyes open.
我会用红外线标记他们
I'm gonna paint these guys with the infrared
保证我们的行动同步
so we're all on the same page.
大家都看到这个人了吗
Everybody got this guy?
- 收到 - 我看到了
- Roger. - Yeah. I got him.
这一个
This guy?
- 看到了 - 看到了
- Got him. - Got him.
这一个
This guy?
- 看到了 - 看到了
- Got him. - Got him.
- 还有那一个 - 三个人
- How about that guy? - Three.
我看到他了
I see him.
瞧瞧这些家伙
Look at these guys.
好像小孩子在玩捉迷藏
It's like kids playing hide and seek.
我看到有AK步枪
I got AKs.
得把他们引过来
You guys got to draw them in.
引过来 他们看不见你
Draw them in. They cannot see you.
我们有夜视 他们没有
We have night vision, they don't.
现在把灯关了
Turn the lights off now.
要让他们靠多近
How much closer do we let them get?
他们有武器
They got weapons.
快下令 隆 他们就在跟前了
Come on, Rone, they're right here.
我看到大概有25到30个敌人
We got about 25-30 Tangos.
我负责右翼
I'm taking the right side.
泰格 你中弹了吗
Tig, you hit?
你还好吗
You all right?
打在防弹衣上了
Armor caught it.
那是个错误
That's a mistake.
兄弟们 我们打退他们了
Dude, we kicked their asses!
不知道我应该感到幸运还是不幸
I don't know if I'm feeling lucky or unlucky.
他们以为是走进
They thought they were walking into
另一个临时大使馆
another temporary embassy.
找错地方了 老兄
Not here, brother.
主管 给我们弄点空中支援
Chief, get us some air support,
他妈的什么支援都行
Get us fucking something!
全球响应人员 报到
GRS, check in.
B栋布恩 坦托 没事
All good, Boon, Tanto, Building B.
D栋 停火了
D was out of the fight.
三号塔 泰格和奥兹 好的不能再好了
Tower 3, Tig and Oz, never better.
我扶你起来 别站
Let's get you up. Stay down.
敌方的房子里还有动静 泰
Bad guy's house is still active, Ty.
我们盯着了
We got eyes on.
收到
Roger that.
他们把灯都打烂了
They shot out all the lights.
第一波人完成任务了
First wave got the job done.
- 你想喝咖啡吗 - 太他妈想了
- You want a coffee? - I sure as hell do.
我猜无人机看到三十个人在打我们了
I guess the drone saw 30 guys shooting at us.
快点来啊
Come on.
二号技术加密安全
Secure with tech two encryption.
为什么这个牧羊人枪战之后还在闲逛
Why is this shepherd walking around after a gunfight?
太反常了
So bizarre.
我快要被这些羊吓疯了
These sheep freak me out.
可能会有人在羊群里乱开枪的
Somebody could take a potshot from in there.
我觉得不太安全
I don't think it's safe.
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
戴夫 你得放松点
Dave, you got to slow it down, buddy.
你太拼命了
You're working too hard.
我别无选择
Look, this isn't a choice for me.
我们没保护好大使
We lost the Ambassador.
这笔账可是算在我们头上 不是你们
That's on our heads, not yours.
我懂的 我知道你在想什么
And, look, I get it. I know what you're thinking.
但如果斯科特在安全屋里向暴徒开枪的话
But if Scott had fired on that mob from the safe haven,
他的位置就会暴露
it would've given away his position.
那样我们不会有一丝机会
And we wouldn't have had a fighting chance in hell
把他救出来
to get him out.
所以这场战斗 我要全程参与
So, I'm in this fight. All night.
我知道你会的
I know you are.
我懂的 兄弟
I get it, man.
凌晨 1:28 班加西国际机场
12 英里外
嘿 怎么回事 我们的车呢
Hey! Hey, what's going on? Where are our rides?
这些利比亚官僚只会
Look, this is all screwed-up
搞砸事情
Libyan bureaucracy. Okay.
谁来开车 谁先走
Who drives, who goes first,
肯定谁拿的钱最多
and of course who gets paid the most.
我们没时间讨论这个
We don't have time for this!
你和他们说自己搞定
You tell them to figure it out.
把他们看紧了
Keep a close watch on them.
我们不知道这些人是敌是友
We don't know who's good and who's bad.
收到
Copy that.
我们着陆了 但是遇到了麻烦
We're wheels down, but we got a problem.
有什么发现吗 咖啡给我
What do you got? Coffee.
- 阿莫尔 - 怎么了
- Amahl. - Yes.
告诉他让他
Tell him he should assemble his men
尽快集结自己的部队
as quickly as possible
我们会付他钱
and that we will pay him.
- 他要求现金 - 现金 可以
- Cash. - Cash? Fine.
多长时间 他们多久能到这
When? When can they be here?
主管在哪
Where's the Chief?
让他尽快把
Just bring...That he brings his
他的部队带过来
fucking men as soon as possible
然后把我们救出去
and get us the hell out of here.
外面现在一团糟
Looting the compound.
鲜血滴入水中 会引来饥饿的鲨鱼
Blood in the water. Sharks are circling.
的黎波里的队伍被困在机场了
The Tripoli team is stuck at the airport.
他们需要护送的人 他们并不熟悉这座城市
They need an escort. They don't know the city.
利比亚政府不表达下爱意吗
No love from the Libyan government?
他们的人要么下班回家了
They've gone home for the night.
要么就是不接我们的电话
Or just not answering.
那我们的自己人呢
What about ours?
他们接电话了吗
They picking up the phone?
我正在让人联系
I'm working on it.
无人机在天上盘旋
That drone feed's up.
它看到的情况比我们还多
They're seeing everything we see and more.
五角大楼 - 任务指挥中心
克罗地亚 -  美军第十特种部队 准备重新部署
主管 将军已经确认可以调来班加西的部队了
Chief, general have identified the forces that can move to Benghazi.
我们说话这会他们正在集结
They're spinning up as we speak.
国务院一直在请求
State has been asked
东道国的入境许可
to secure the approval from the host nation.
将军 这很有可能是敌方机场
General, this could be a hostile airport,
所以我们要考虑每一种选择
so we are considering every option.
我明白 现在局势不明
Understood. It's a fluid situation.
但是那有许多美国公民被困
But there are a lot of Americans stuck there.
我说先把士兵空运过去
I say we get them airborne,
然后再做决定
then we can make our decision.
格伦 我们已经在这里浪费三个小时了
Hey, Glen, we've been waiting for three hours.
我们能不能直接征用这些车辆然后出发
Can we just commandeer these vehicles and go?
进去不是问题 怎么出来才是问题
Getting in isn't the problem. Getting out again is.
你能否告诉他们
Can you explain to them
如果在这浪费时间
that if this bullshit ends up
导致美国人死亡的话
costing American lives,
我会回来
I'm gonna come back here
亲手宰了他们
and cut all their throats myself,
先告诉这家伙
starting with him.
告诉他
You tell him that.
真他妈的荒诞
What a shitshow.
国务院收到一份班加西医疗中心的报告
State got a report from the Benghazi Medical Center
报告说一群利比亚人
that said a crowd of Libyans
送了一个美国男性入院
brought in an American male
活着的
alive.
他们用的是斯科特·威克兰德的电话
They used Scott Wickland's phone,
据说是从克利斯的口袋里找到的
said it came from Chris' pocket.
他们可能是想把我们引出去
Could try and draw us in.
小心埋伏
Watch out for an ambush.
你看见了什么
What do you see?
我不太清楚看到的是什么
I'm not sure what it is.
要么有坏人在羊群下面匍匐前进
Either the bad guys are crawling under the sheep
要么就是羊群在发情
or the sheep are humping.
晚上两点半的时候发情
2:30 at night?
我对羊的习性一无所知
I don't know anything about sheep.
小心点
Watch your step.
奥兹
Oz.
蹲低一点 蹲低一点
Stay low. Stay low.
我给你带了糖和一些喝的
I brought you candy bars and some drinks.
你头受伤了
Your head.
没事
It's nothing.
你还需要什么别的东西吗
You need anything else?
好吧
Well,
要是有一把躺椅就太棒了
a lawn chair wouldn't be bad.
好的 没问题
Right. No problem.
战斗机是空对空攻击 攻击机是空对地攻击
再来架攻击机
And a gunship.
我觉得那个可能弄不到
I don't think we're gonna be able to get you that.
有几架F16战斗机也勉强可以
I'd settle for a few F16s.
战斗机在城市上空低空飞行
Low fly-by over the city would
就能让他们感受到对上帝和美国的畏惧
put the fear of God and the United States in them.
为我们争取几个小时时间
Buy us a few more hours.
你们还能坚持多久
How long can you hold them off?
有多少敌人 多强火力
Any large force with any real ordnance,
我一无所知
I don't know.
你在这和家里有熟人吗
You got contacts here and at home?
去联系一下吧
Start making some calls.
嘿 脱衣舞娘来了
Hey, the stripper's here!
- 这是你的衣服 - 来的真及时
- Here are your clothes. - About time.
楼下情况怎么样了
How are the Jason Bournes doing downstairs?
每个人都很害怕
Everyone's scared.
我刚收到我表哥的
I just got a text from my cousin,
警告信息
you know, a warning,
让我们趁早离开这里
saying to leave before it's too late.
还有好消息吗
More good news.
有更具体的建议吗
Anything more specific than that?
我觉得我们不再需要翻译了 阿莫尔
I don't think we need an interpreter anymore, Amahl.
你干得不错 你应该离开
You did good. You should go.
不 我要留下和你们在一起
No. I'm staying here with you guys.
我会在楼下呆着
I'll be downstairs.
我得在离开利比亚之前
I'm gonna have to break up
和他分手
with him before we leave Libya.
你们在这开派对
How do you leave me on D
居然把我丢在D楼
when the party's right here?
关于大使还活着这事
Hey, about this whole Ambo story,
我不相信
I don't buy it.
如果他还活着
And if he is still alive,
格伦的队伍得先去救他
Glen's team's gonna get him out first.
如果他们去了 那就没人来救我们了
If they do, they're not gonna get to us.
所以我们得准备在这里再坚持一段时间了
So we've got to be prepared to be here for a while.
主管说国内的新闻已经在报道了
Chief said it was on the news back home.
街头示威抗议什么的 反伊斯兰的电影
Something about street protests. Anti-Islamic films.
我们没有听到任何示威抗议
We didn't hear any protests.
是在电视新闻上报道的 哥们
It was reported in the news, buddy.
你看见了吗
You see that?
在走私者小路的尽头 你看看
At the end of Smuggler's Alley. Take a look.
可能是要开辟第二战场
Could be a second front forming.
或者是一些无知的围观群众
Or an audience gathering to watch the show.
主管
Hey, Chief.
我知道你今天晚上妙语如珠
I know you've had some pearls of wisdom tonight,
但是我们是否在等友军支援
but are we expecting any friendlies?
我看到许多人在活动
I got a lot of movement out here.
看样子我们又要遭到攻击了
Looks like we're gonna get hit again.
戴夫 你负责僵尸之地 奥兹 跟我走
Dave, take Zombieland. Oz, with me.
加强防护 加强防护
Grab a shield. Grab a shield.
主管 让他们把无人机上的
Chief, tell them to get the Hellfire on
导弹准备好
that Pred ready.
警告
Be advised,
无人机发现大量车辆和人员聚集在停车场
ISR saying that cars and bodies are massing
正向我们的西面靠近
in the parking lot to our west.
没错 主管 两分钟前
Yeah, Chief, I just put
我才在无线电里报告过
that out over the radio about two minutes ago.
告诉无人机驾驶 他们真是没用
Tell the ISR guys they're pretty much worthless.
自作聪明的家伙
Fucking smartass.
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on!
发送
Send.
主管 有三十个人正在靠近
Chief, we got 30 guys approaching.
那玩意开火时声音大吗
Hey. Is that thing loud?
挺大的
Oh, yeah.
我忘带耳塞了
I forgot my earplugs.
注意你们负责的区域
Keep your eyes on your assigned quadrants.
最好不要遭到侧面突袭
We don't want to get flanked.
准备好了吗 泰格
You ready, Tig?
- 准备好了 - 小心对方的诡计
- Here we go. - Watch for different tactics.
奥兹
Oz?
怎么不用卫生棉条塞耳
You lose your tampon?
泰格 小心松树那个方向
Tig, watch the pine trees.
那是什么东西
What is this?
这辆车想干嘛
What is this yo-yo doing?
你觉得他们不知道我们有夜视境吗
You think they don't know we have night vision?
全球响应人员 所有人不要开火
GRS, I want everybody to hold.
距离三十码
Thirty yards.
不不 你要干什么
No, no, no, no. What are you doing?
不 别这样做 操
No, don't do that. Fuck!
趴下
Get down!
什么 说大声点
What? Louder!
停火 停止开火
Stop! Stop shooting!
二月十七日旅说你们正在向他们射击
17 Feb says you're firing at them!
是他们先开枪的
Somebody started shooting at us first!
而且他们现在还在射击
And they're still fucking shooting at us!
告诉他们先停火
Tell them to stop shooting at us
然后我们就会停火
and we'll stop shooting at them.
要是他们还在射击 你们就打回去
If they're shooting at you, just fucking shoot back!
我就是这个意思
That's what I'm telling you!
有三十多个人在对着我们开火
We got 30 guys firing at us!
二月十七日旅 才怪
17 Feb, my ass.
泰格 注意林木线
Tig, tree line.
他们从侧面的僵尸之地攻过来了
They're flanking us from Zombieland!
- 转移位置 - 正在转移
- Move! - Moving!
楼下那个窗户
Upstairs window.
公共汽车那边
Bus.
看到一个大炸弹正从那出来
We got big ordnance coming out of there.
攻击公共汽车
Hit the bus!
这一炮是要打我们的
That one's for us.
这次你们别想逃
You're not getting away this time!
你觉得他们泄气了吗
You think they're losing heart?
所有人 来这边
Everyone, over here.
给我找出所有能到达我们这的空军基地
Find me every airbase in the area that can reach us.
找到任何快速反应部队
Find me any quick response teams,
任何附近的海军航母战斗群
any Navy carrier battle groups in the vicinity, now.
我听说在克罗地亚有一支战区指挥官应急连
I hear they have a US CIF team in Croatia.
距此有两个小时的飞行时间
That's a two-hour flight.
位于意大利东北部的阿维亚诺市
西格奈拉基地 阿维亚诺空军基地 班加西
Sigonella, Aviano, Benghazi.
- 阿维亚诺离这多远 - 七百英里
- How far is Aviano? - 700 miles.
有一架F16战斗机全天候待命
There's an F16, 365 days 24/7.
那里是一个快速反应基地
It's a quick response base.
行 让飞机从西格奈拉基地起飞
Well, bring it in from Sigonella.
从意大利过来就他妈两步路而已
It's a fucking puddle jump from Italy to here.
是二十分钟航程
It's 20 minutes.
我不是请求火力支援
I'm not requesting firepower.
我只希望你们能
All I want is that you give these
来个低空飞行
assholes outside our gate
告诉我们门外的混蛋"滚蛋"
a low, loud "Fuck you" Flyover.
我的权限
My authority?
My authority
就是你们如果不派人来
is that if you don't send,
美国公民就会死
Americans are going to die.
包括正在和你通话的这个人
Including the one talking to you right now.
你看到了吗 哥们
You see that, dude?
有人在那边的石头上面
There's guys on those rocks over there.
那里什么都没有
There's nothing there.
你眼睛花了
Your eyes are playing tricks, man.
去休息一会吧
Why don't you go take a break?
不 我还行
No. I'm okay.
泰格 去休息一下
Tig, take a break.
泰格 下去吧 我来替你
Hey, Tig. Go on down, man. I'll spell you.
那些外交安全局的家伙
Oh, those State guys.
戴夫在C栋楼顶
Dave up on C,
你真该看看他的神情
you should see the look in his eyes.
这些家伙这辈子
These guys are gonna
都忘不了今晚的经历
relive this night for the rest of their lives.
要说我的心态 从未有那种感觉
My whole mindset? Never feel that.
开枪 杀人 总是如此
You go down shooting, balls out, every time.
你怎么样 兄弟
How you doing, brother?
停火间隙才是最难受的 不是吗
Down time's the worst, isn't it?
肾上腺素消退之后
Adrenaline leaves and
你就会开始胡思乱想
your mind just starts to wander.
没错
Oh, yeah.
今天晚上我还没有想过我的家人
I haven't thought about my family once tonight.
现在我很想念她们
Thinking about them now.
就在此时此地
Up here in the middle of all this,
我在想我的女儿们
I'm thinking about my girls, man.
我在想
Thinking
她们日后会怎么评论我
what would they say about me?
"他死于一个他没必要去的地方"
"He died in a place he didn't need to be,"
"死于一场他不知为何而战的战争"
"In a battle over something he doesn't understand,"
"死于一个对他没有任何意义的国家"
"In a country that meant nothing to him."
每次我回家 回到贝基和姑娘们身边时
Every time I go home to becky and those girls,
我会想就是这样了
I think this is it.
我要留在这里
I'm gonna stay.
然后事情来了 最后我又回到这里
And then something happens and I end up back here.
为什么会这样 为什么我不能回家呢
Why is that? Why can't I go home?
为什么我不能回家然后留在家里呢
Why can't I go home and just stay there?
战士们可不是训练来退役的 杰克
Warriors aren't trained to retire, Jack.
贝基怀孕了
Becky's pregnant.
你没开玩笑吧
You kidding me?
她今天告诉我的
She told me today.
那不能是我们的最后通话
And that can't be the last call.
不能是最后通话
That can't be the last call,
因为我现在坐在这里
'cause I'm sitting up here
想象着
and I'm thinking about
由别人来抚养我的孩子们
some other guy raising these girls.
兄弟 我很抱歉
Man, I'm sorry.
- 不不 - 我不应该...
- No, no, hey... - I shouldn't have...
不 兄弟 没关系
Mmm-mmm. No, man, no... It's all right.
我明白 好吗
I get it. Okay?
你想陪伴他们
You go to them.
我知道这种处境是什么感受
I know what it's like to be in a place like this,
让别的男人抚养你的孩子
let another man raise your children.
年轻的时候
When I was young,
我参军献身国家伟业
I was giving myself to something bigger.
杰克 现在这伟大事业结束了
Jack, that something bigger's gone now.
但你刚出生的儿子呢
But your new son?
卡伊是你的第二次机会
Kai is your second chance.
我应该还算一个不错的父亲吧
I might actually not be a half-bad father.
"所有的神 天堂和地狱
"All the gods, all the heavens,
都在你的心中"
all the hells are within you."
什么意思
What is that?
之前布恩告诉我的
Something Boon dropped on me earlier.
之后这句话就一直在我脑海里盘旋
And it's just been going around in my head all night.
我们有几个问题现在弄清楚了
We have some clarity on a couple of issues.
的黎波里的小队已经解决了机场的争端
The Tripoli team has cleared the airport,
他们正在来的路上
and they are on their way.
你没开玩笑吧 太及时了
You've got to be kidding me. It's about time.
我们也得到了证实
We also have confirmation.
确实是史蒂文斯大使
It is Ambassador Stevens.
但是之前报告中说他还活着的消息
But the earlier report that he was admitted alive
并不属实
was inaccurate.
他在别墅后面被人发现
He was apparently found in the back of the villa
被一群利比亚人送去了医院
and brought to the hospital by a crowd of Libyans.
他死于吸入过多烟尘
Cause of death is smoke inhalation.
操
Shit.
我们本可以救他的
You know, we could've saved him
如果我们接到求救就行动
if we'd gone when we got the call.
我们本可以救下他们俩的
We could've saved them both.
没错
Yep.
敌人肯定会想出对策
You know, they're gonna get this figured out.
下次会开着武装皮卡来进攻
Come at us with technicals next.
到时候我们只能离开楼顶
We'll have to get down off this roof
和他们正面交火
and engage them direct.
是的 我知道
Yeah, I know.
我从未真正感到过害怕
I never really get scared.
这是不是很奇怪
Is that weird?
在枪林弹雨中
Whenever bullets start to fly,
我总感觉自己受到了庇护
I always feel protected.
你知道 这就像是...
You know, like it's...
只要我做的是正确的事情
As long as I'm doing the right thing,
上帝会保佑我
God'll take care of me.
但这听上去很疯狂 对吧
But that's crazy, right?
和你说的其他事情一样疯狂
Not any more than everything else you say.
希望上帝也有幽默感
Hope God has a sense of humor.
没错
Yeah.
我想我们很快就能知道了
I guess we'll find out soon enough.
今天我和家人聊得很开心
I had a good call home today.
然后呢
Yeah?
我和孩子们通了话
Talked to my kids.
我也是
Me, too.
我们需要一个在A栋的人
Hey, we need somebody on Building A
监视入侵者
eyeballing our visitors.
好吧 就是我了
Yep. That's me.
你还好吧 兄弟
You good, brother?
没事
Yep.
喂 伙计
Hey, man.
这挺好玩的 是吧
It's been fun, right?
是的
Yeah.
挺好玩的
It's been fun.
什么 你是说他们不知道具体地址
What, do you mean they don't know where it is?
我们的利比亚朋友真帮不上什么忙
Our Libyan friends here aren't much help.
基地 我们迷路了
Okay, annex, we're officially lost.
谷歌和苹果语音助手都不知道你们的位置
Neither Google or Siri know where the fuck you are.
告诉的黎波里小队 我在画圈显示我们的位置
Let Tripoli ops know I'm lassoing our location.
现在应该看得见红外线在画圈了
There should be an IR lasso visible right now.
那里 就在前面 我看见了
There. There it is up ahead. I see it.
哥们 我可以吞下好几个煎饼
Man, I could crush some pancakes.
抹着黄油 再来点鲜奶油
Smothered with butter. Some of that whipped cream.
撒点巧克力屑 我现在什么都吃得下
Chocolate chips. I'd do any of it right now.
喂 伙计们
Hey, guys.
我不知道现在说这个是否合适
I don't know if this is an awkward time to tell you,
但离开领事馆后
but I've had to take a crap
我拉过一泡大便
ever since we left the consulate.
这信息量太大了 哥们
Way too much information, brother.
喂 主管
Hey, Chief.
我们在等的车不止一辆吧
We're expecting more than one car, correct?
我不知道有任何援军要来 一点消息也没有
I am not aware of any friendlies. No word.
我现在看见三个人
I got three Tangos in a car
坐着一辆车朝前门来了
coming up to the front gate, right now.
车速很快
Coming in hot.
他们停下了
They stopped.
来吧
Come on.
他最好带着武器
He better have a weapon.
快掏枪吧
Show me a gun.
可能是汽车炸弹
Could be a car bomb.
不是 没枪 只拿出了手机
Nope. No gun, just a phone.
我要干了这家伙 隆
I want to shoot this guy, Rone.
隆 我要打爆他的脸
Rone, I'm gonna shoot him in the face.
他在干吗 他掉头了
What's he doing? He's turning around.
他开走了
He's pulling out.
走了
He's taking off.
可能是用手机
Could be someone using their cell phone
来获取靶点坐标
to get target coordinates.
好吧 怪事又开始了
All right. Weird shit's starting to happen now.
德克萨斯独立战争中最重要的一次战役 发生于1835-1836年
阿拉莫要塞最后被围困了13天 以几乎全部德克萨斯人的壮烈牺牲而告终
我快受够这场
I've had just about enough of
2012版的阿拉莫战役了
this 2012 Alamo bullshit.
不能现在就离开这里吗
Can we get the fuck out of here now?
我的一个耳膜破了 有点聋
I know I blew an eardrum earlier, but
吟诵是不是全停了
did all the chanting just stop?
不是好现象
That can't be good.
伙计们 情况不妙 游骑兵们都知道
Guys, this sucks. Every Ranger knows
法国人和印第安人总是在拂晓发动进攻
dawn is when the French and Indians attack.
我觉得今晚很走运 坦托
I'm feeling lucky tonight, Tanto.
主管
Chief.
我们等的是卡车
Are we expecting some trucks,
或大型武装车吗
or big mounted technicals?
友军 友军 装甲部队到了
Blue, blue! Cavalry's here!
虽然看上去火力不太够
Yeah. You're looking a little light,
但依然非常欢迎
but welcome to the party!
中东永远不会让你们失望
Middle East never lets you down.
品貌出众 组织有序 导航准确
Personable, organized, easy to navigate.
让我好想喝上一杯
Makes me need a fucking drink!
海豹突击队员的别称
我的蛙人兄弟在哪里
Where's my frogman?
C楼 顶上
Building C, up top!
我们可以撤了吗
We gonna exfil now?
带我们去的黎波里 兄弟 一定让你一醉方休
Get us to Tripoli, brother, I'll get you wasted.
利比亚之盾联盟 是2012年成立的反卡扎菲武装力量组织 但利比亚政府认定其为恐怖组织和伊斯兰原教旨主义军事组织
我是利比亚之盾的指挥官
I'm the Commander of the Libyan Shield.
谢谢你们赶来
Thank you for coming.
长官 我们奉命来销毁
Sir, we're tasked with
敏感文件
sensitive document destruction.
- 差点就来晚了 - 你好 格伦
- Not a moment too soon. - Hey, Glen!
谁喊来了机场专车啊
Anyone call an airport limo?
近来可好 小老弟
What's up, brother Bub?
见到你真开心 兄弟
Good to see you, brother.
抱歉来晚了 在礼品店耽搁了一会
Sorry I'm late. I got hung up in the gift shop.
你们这真是一团糟啊
Oh. You guys made a mess up here.
本该等你去救大使的
Would've waited for you,
但无线电里哭天喊地的救命
but people crying and dying over the radio, man.
我们实在听不下去
We didn't have the heart for it.
隆
Hey, Rone,
很想告诉你一切都结束了 但实在不行
I'd like to tell you it's over, but it isn't.
这有二十四名中情局职员
The 24 CIA staffers here,
五位外交安全局的
plus five State guys,
六名全球反应人员 外加我们
plus six GRS, plus us.
明白 人太多了
I get it. Too many.
喷气式飞机装不下
There's no room in the jet.
你们能在这
You think you can hold things down here
再撑几个小时吗
for a few more hours?
告诉你吧
I'll tell you what.
这些都是勇猛无畏的斗士
These are some hellish warriors.
无论何时与他们并肩作战都是我的荣幸
I'd be lucky to have their back any day.
- 喂 戴夫 - 在
- Hey, Dave! - Yo.
你的幸运日 下去吧
Lucky day. Head on down.
- 一路顺风 伙计 - 谢谢
- Safe travels, buddy. - Thanks.
我去拿我的东西
I'll grab my gear.
嗨 席尔瓦在哪儿
Hey, where's Silva at?
在D楼顶上 - 是吗
- Over on D. - Yeah?
我没想到你会来
I didn't think you were coming.
还以为你有更好的差事呢
Figured you had something better to do.
的确有 哥们
Dude, I was.
都是那句
Then there's all that
"绝不抛下海豹战友"的鬼话
"Never leave a brother SEAL behind" Bullshit,
让我来到了这里
so here I am.
我们要去机场的路还远呢
Long ride to the airport ahead of us.
我去看看他们在耽搁什么
I'll see what the hold-up is.
喂喂 你们到底去哪
Hey, hey, hey! Where the hell are you guys going?
胆小鬼
Chickenshit!
伙计们
Guys.
你们听到了吗
Did anyone else hear that?
伙计们 那是迫击炮吗
Guys, is that a mortar?
迫击炮来了 快躲起来
Mortars incoming. Get cover!
我中弹了
I'm hit! I'm hit!
奥兹 我来了
Oz, I'm coming!
隆 隆
Rone! Rone!
这里是兰利 说一下你们的情况
This is Langley. Give us your stat.
还好吗 看起来不妙啊
You okay? Looks bad.
鲍勃 回答我
Bob, answer.
A楼 情况如何 回报
Building A, what's going on? Check in.
叫三角洲部队的人赶紧上来
Get Deltas up on the roof now!
友军 友军 正从外而进来
Blue, blue. Going external.
检查一下西面
Check that field to the west.
杰克 这副吊样你想的到吗
Jack, you believe this shit?
住手 你这样会越弄越糟
Stop. Stop, you're gonna fuck it up even more.
好 准备好了吗
All right. You ready?
一 二 三
One, two, three.
杰克 我尽力了
Jack, Jack. I tried, man.
别担心 别担心
Don't worry about it. Don't worry about it.
我带你出去
Let's get you out. Let's get you out.
扶我起来
Get me up.
能走吗
Can you walk?
能走 帮我一下
Yeah. Help me out. Help me out.
我来了
I'm coming!
戴夫 自己人 别开枪
Dave, Dave, hey, I'm on your side. Don't shoot me.
没事的 给我 给我
It's okay, It's okay. I got it, I got it!
我马上回来
I'll be right back. Yeah.
我不想死
I want to live.
- 是的 我马上回来 - 别走
- Yeah. I'm coming right back. - Don't!
我的枪 我要枪
My pistol, I need my pistol.
- 给我手枪 - 好
- Give me my pistol. - Okay.
给你
Here we go. Here we go.
救援马上就来 挺住 挺住
Men are on the way, all right? Hang in. Hang in.
格伦 格伦
Glen. Glen.
上帝 请你照顾他
God, watch over him.
为他指引天堂之路
Guide him where he needs to be.
保佑他的家人
Take care of his family.
主管
Chief.
戴夫伤得很重
Dave's hurt really bad.
叫人上去看看他
Get somebody up there to see him.
隆 我们需要紧急治疗 完毕
Rone, we need you in medical immediately. Over.
请回答 隆
Answer! Rone!
隆已经和我们永别了
Rone's not with us anymore.
奥兹 我能做什么
Oz, how can I help?
带我去医务室
Get me to medical.
再不来 戴夫
Dave's gonna bleed out fast
会很快失血致死的
if you don't get up here.
我需要止血带
I'm gonna need some tourniquets.
把桌子理干净
Clear that table back there.
压住伤口
Put pressure on that wound.
把我脱光 检查出血口
Get me naked. Check for bleeds.
好
Okay.
创伤剪 在架子最上层右边
Trauma shears, top shelf on the right.
小心 小心
Hey, hey, hey. Careful, careful, careful.
我可不想又被扎伤
I don't want to get stabbed, too.
你们干什么 别别别
What are you doing? No! No, no, no!
喂 不是感情用事的时候
Hey! It's not the time!
敌人还在外面呢
The enemy is still out there!
我们走
Let's go!
我请求了空中支援
I called for air support.
但他们不来
It never came.
给我看下
Show it to me.
我弄丢了大使 伙计
I lost the Ambo, man.
你对吗啡过敏吗
Are you allergic to morphine?
我弄丢了大使 戴夫 怎么办
I lost the Ambo, Dave. What do I do?
闭嘴 拿把枪门口站着去
Shut up and go get a gun on that door.
快去
Now!
布恩 你听到卡车声音了吗
You hear that, Boon? You hear trucks?
主管
Chief.
我们有在等待任何援军吗
Are we expecting any friendlies?
上帝啊
Oh, my God.
我看见有四十 五十辆车 包括武装卡车
I got 40, 50 vehicles, including technicals.
我不知道
I don't know.
完了 伙计们 全完了
It's over, guys. It's fucking over.
妈的一支大部队啊
A fucking massive heavy force.
上膛 上膛
Cock it, cock it.
对我来说
As far as I'm concerned,
不到最后就不算完
this isn't over till it ends.
不是他们死就是我们亡
That's when they're all dead or we are.
天啊
Oh, Lord! Oh, Jesus!
伙计们 我觉得他们是自己人
Guys, I think they're with us.
他们是自己人
They're with us!
快走 快走
Move, move!
SCIF全称Sensitive Compartmented Information Facility  敏感信息隔离设施
外面不安全 快走
It's not safe out here. Keep going.
快 上车
Hurry! Get in the trucks!
他们可能还会来的
They could still be coming.
快点 伙计们 上卡车
Come on, guys, get in the trucks.
快点 这里不安全 快走
Come on. It's not safe out here. Come on. Let's go.
上上上 快点 快点
Up, up, up! Please, please, please.
快点 伙计们
Come on, guys!
主管 该走了
Chief, it's time.
不 我留下
No, I'm staying.
长官 这是最后的车了
Sir, this is the last ride out.
知道 我不走
Yeah, I know. I'm staying.
我还要搜集情报
I've got Intel to collect.
我们走吧
Okay. Let's go!
还在等什么
What's the hold-up?
你们主管 他不想撤退
Your Chief, he won't exfil!
这里不安全
It's not safe out here!
- 你怎么了 - 我有活要干
- You what? - I've got work to do.
我留下
I'm staying.
留下干嘛
For what?
想让更多像泰和格伦
So that more guys like Ty and Glen
一样的人回来吗
have to come back here?
再来救你的小命
And save your ass again?
你在这的事情完了
You're done here.
他妈的快点上车
Now, get in the fucking car!
阿莫尔
Amahl.
我们挺过来了 伙计
We made it, man.
来吧 上车
Come on, get in the truck.
- 我要回家了 - 什么
- I'm going home. - What?
真抱歉 这一切不该发生的
I'm so sorry. This should never have happened.
喂
Hey.
你们国家得收拾好这个烂摊子 阿莫尔
Your country's got to figure this shit out, Amahl.
我走着进入这个国家 出去也要用走的
I walked into this country, I'm walking out.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不知道你们是怎么挺过来的
I don't know how you survived all that.
但我知道其余的人是怎么过来的
But I know how the rest of us did.
你们今晚表现不错
You guys did well tonight.
认识你们这样的美国人我感到很自豪
I'm proud to know Americans like you.
我们的飞机还要等几个小时
Couple more hours till our plane.
大使的遗体就快到了
Ambassador's body's just about here.
你好 长官
Hi, sir.
车能给我吗
Can I have car?
拿去
Yeah.
那些迫击炮
There's no way.
不可能是偶然击中我们的
No way those mortars found us by chance.
肯定几天或几周前就瞄准我们了
Had to be set up on us days or weeks ago.
听着
Listen.
要是换成其他六个人 我想不一定挺得过来
Any other six guys, I don't think we'd make it.
我们昨晚并肩作战是上天注定的
I think we were meant to be together last night.
你们觉得主管的结果会如何
How do you think the Chief's eval is gonna go?
会得到一枚勋章 等着瞧吧
He's going to get a medal. You'll see.
三角洲部队呢
And the Deltas?
全体授予勋章
Yep. Medals. All of them.
那我们呢
And what about us?
一千比一的赔率 很简单
The odds were 1,000-to-1, easy.
我们还想得到什么
What do we get?
我们可以回家
We get to go home.
利比亚运输机
Libyan transport.
依然不是美国飞机
Still no Americans.
喂
Hey.
是我
It's me.
我想第一时间让你得到消息 我们这...
I wanted you to hear it from me first. We had a...
出了点事
A problem here.
无论你在新闻里听到什么 现在都结束了
Whatever you hear on the news, it's over now.
我不干了
I'm done.
我要回家了
I'm coming home.
再也不走了
For good.
不
No.
不 我只是幸运 我...
No, I'm just lucky. I...
幸运而已
I'm just lucky.
他没能挺过来
He didn't make it.
隆回不了家了
Rone's not coming home.
我非常爱你
I love you so much.
"所有的神 天堂与地狱
"All the gods, all the heavens,
都在你的心中"
all the hells are within you."
什么意思
What is that?
之前布恩告诉我的
Something Boon dropped on me earlier.
之后这句话就一直在我脑海里盘旋
It's just been rattling around in my head all night.
全体二十六名中情局职员和五名外交安全局特工安全回家
袭击事件发生十天后 十万利比亚人哀悼克利斯托弗·史蒂文斯大使
利比亚正式沦为一个混乱国家 成了ISIS的根据地
班加西中情局基地主管退休前
荣获了中情局颁发的卓越情报工作勋章
全球响应人员的成员
在私人纪念仪式上获得了合约情报人员勋章
"泰格" - 约翰·泰根从中情局辞职 他和妻子及双胞胎生活在科罗拉多州
"布恩" - 戴夫·班顿从中情局辞职 与家人一起过着平静的生活
"坦托" 克里斯·帕朗托从中情局辞职 他和妻子及两个孩子
生活在内布拉斯加州 目前是保险公估人
"奥兹" - 马克·盖斯特从中情局辞职 为了使他得以享受最好的医疗服务
国防部长将他重新征募入伍
经过十多次手术 现在他的左手已可以使用
他和妻子及女儿们住在科罗拉多州
杰克·席尔瓦从中情局辞职 与妻子及三个孩子一起过着平静的生活
美国人民对不起
这种行为不代表伊斯兰及其先知
克里斯托弗·史蒂文斯大使
西恩·史密斯
"小老弟" 格伦·道尔蒂
"隆" 泰隆·伍兹
纪念这些为国捐躯的中情局成员
向
隆 和 格伦
致敬
导演
迈克尔·贝
詹姆斯·贝吉·戴尔
约翰·卡拉辛斯基
麦克斯·马蒂尼